[music]
Heat. Heat.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Heat. Heat.
>> [music]
[music]
Heat. Heat.
>> [music]
>> Heat. Heat.
Heat. Heat.
Welcome Living Mana Church family, we
are so happy that you are here with us
on the Sabbath day. It is such a
blessing to be with all of you from all
around the world. Please put in the chat
where you're viewing from. If this is
your very first time, put a one in the
chat so we can say a very special
welcome to you. I know it was great last
uh last week to meet um some of our
viewing audience um in New York City.
There was just uh we got to see a lot of
people and that was a lot of fun.
>> Yep. Yep. Uh we um you know we traveled
and I'll
uh
say that it was a very blessed
>> it was
>> time. Some of our members were watching
us
>> preach at Living Mana
>> and some of our members were watching us
preach in Brooklyn, New York.
>> Yeah, that was great.
>> And uh yeah, it was uh it was a good
experience.
>> It was a great experience to meet so
many people
>> uh that are that view and and get to
just fellowship with you guys. And so we
know we have a large viewing audience uh
in New York. Um you guys tell us every
week like watching from this part of New
York and here and there. So we just want
to welcome everyone um again and all of
our viewing audience from New York. It
was good to see some of you last so last
week. So please put continue to put in
the chat where you're viewing from and
again put a one if this is your very
first time. Living u Mana family please
welcome continue to welcome um everyone
in the chat. tell them happy Sabbath and
that you are happy to see them here and
we're happy to see you here as well.
>> Amen. And uh again, we're kind of
looking forward to uh our Sabbath school
today because we are continuing
>> our study on the fruit of the spirit
>> and uh we have our guest with us again
and we'll introduce him a little bit
later. But uh we're going to be talking
about the spirit of patience.
>> Yes. And man, do we need it.
>> Yes. I was was needing patience today.
>> Yes,
>> we're always needing patience. Always
needing to exercise patience. Not and I
should this is probably I'm probably
getting into the Sabbath school
[laughter] at this moment but not just
um I mean in our daily walk in our life
and even with our relationship with God
>> because sometimes it's so hard to have
faith because a lot of times with faith
you have to wait and have patience
>> and we're like God why aren't you
answering like you know is this coming
and you know God is like
>> I move on my time and my time is going
to be perfect so have
>> the fruit of the spirit of patience. And
we'll get into that deeper for Sabbath
school.
>> But also we uh have a baptism baptisms I
should say next week. So we're excited
about that. Um we'll give you more
information just tell you about that.
And if you're wanting to get baptized,
you'll get more information about that
and the divine uh worship service time.
So uh we're happy to be able to do this.
You know, people say like, "How do you
do communion? How do you do baptism?"
And communion was amazing last week. It
was it was just
>> it was wonderful. Um the sp Holy Spirit
was really there. And so we did that
online. We still have the the grape
juice um and the communion bread. Even
the foot washing. Yes, we can do all of
that, guys.
>> Being online does not stop us from
having a church and fellowshipping and
having community. It's amazing. And um
when it's time for baptism, Pastor Myers
goes and baptizes
um a group of people, those who are
ready for baptism. So, we are just so
excited about that. And I'm going to
announce it here and I will announce it
again um in at the beginning of the
divine worship service. But next week,
next week we are having our very first
Living Mana Youth Sabbath.
Yes, our youth of Living Mana Church are
taking over. They will be doing the
Sabbath school.
>> They will be doing what I'm doing right
here. They will be welcoming you to
church and to Sabbath school. They will
be doing the prayer time, the
intercessory prayer time and testimony.
They will be doing that and they will be
doing the sermon.
>> So it is the very first LOC youth
Sabbath and we are very excited about
that. So, you will get more information
during divine worship service, but also
um you're going to have to sign up to
get those uh text alerts and mighty
networks because it's all going to be on
there as well.
>> Amen.
>> So, I think it's time for the t-shirt
message.
>> His grace is enough.
>> His grace is enough. And this is a oldie
but goodie. And I say oldie but goodie
because I got this shirt during the
pandemic. Mhm.
>> I know that it was that's when I first
got it. So that's like five years ago.
Um but um the message is just so
powerful that you know so many times um
as you know I'm a mental health
therapist and you know I talk to people
all the time that just feel that um
they're not good enough or um they're
comparing themselves to other people and
all those type of things. And so, you
know, just reminding our ourselves daily
that God's grace is enough to save us.
>> So, we don't have to worry. You know,
the enemy, Satan wants us to worry all
the time, like have anxiety. Am I doing
everything right? Am I going to be this?
Am I going to make it to heaven?
[clears throat] His grace is enough.
It's enough to not leave us how he found
us. Enough to change us and make us the
way that he wants us. And we don't have
to worry.
>> Yeah.
>> We can literally I'm comparing going
back to your servant Sabatis sab
sabatismos and just rest.
>> Yeah.
>> That's how much
>> like we talked about in our Sabbath
school last week. Sleeping.
>> Sleeping. Yes.
>> So that's how much his grace is enough
that we can just
>> we can just chill.
>> We can just relax.
>> The enemy wants us to do exactly
opposite of what God's saying to do.
Just chill. Relax. He wants us to be
worried and have anxiety. Yeah.
>> All the time.
>> Yeah.
>> About our salvation.
>> So that's But yeah, his grace is enough.
His grace is enough to save you.
>> Amen.
>> And fix any problem and situation that
you're in. It's enough for everything.
>> So his grace is enough.
>> Yeah. So I think we're going to go ahead
and uh invite our guests on.
>> Yes.
>> And uh we're going to pray.
>> Yeah. And um we're going to get into uh
the fruit of patience.
>> Yes,
>> the fruit of patience.
>> Something that a lot of people lack.
>> Everybody, [laughter]
>> let's pray.
>> We can cult I mean we can get it. God
can his grace is enough
>> but yeah we need it.
>> Heavenly father we thank you Lord for uh
giving us uh this opportunity to worship
you Lord. And as we study this um this
theme of the fruit of patience, Lord, I
pray that you would guide our thoughts
and that what we share today, Lord, this
morning will be a blessing to those that
are watching. Be with our guests and uh
please Lord speak through us as our
prayer in Jesus name. Amen.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> All right. Well, we would like to
welcome our guest, our panel. They're no
guests to you guys. Hello. Welcome,
welcome Melinda and brother Terry. So
good to see you. Uh we are excited about
today and our topic our fruit of the
spirit patience.
>> So we already Oh no, you're going to
you're going to read. Yeah,
>> I was gonna go I was jumping right. So
Pastor Myers is going to read. Remember,
let me say this, too. I knew I was
forgetting something. Um, while he's
pulling that up, we are our Sabbath
school is going through the book The
Christian Art of War, which is based off
of the book The Art of War by
>> Sunzoo.
>> Sunzoo. Okay. So, Pastor Myers wrote
this book about 161 17 years ago and uh
instead of not showing you how to
physically fight in this world, but how
to spiritually fight. Um and so um we
are now on chapter 4 and uh we are going
through the fruit of the spirit and we
are on the fruit of patience but if you
sign up if you have signed up for mighty
networks because everyone always says
where can I get the book? The book is
out of print. Um we're trying to get it
back in print. Um but right now we are
releasing one chapter at a time on
Mighty Networks. So if you sign up for
Mighty Networks, you can get uh chapters
1 through 4 and you can be studying
along with us. Please put in the chat
you what you have found, what stood out
to you. You are part of this Sabbath
school class with us. And so um yeah.
>> Yes. So last couple of uh uh Sabbath
schools, we've been like reading a
sentence by sentence by sentence and
we've gotten almost no not nowhere, but
we'd read one sentence and then spend
the whole day just on that one sentence.
>> As would say, our minds were blown.
>> So what we're going to do is we're going
to actually read through this entire
section of the spirit of patience. Yes.
>> And then we'll comment on it. Yes. Talk
about it and just build on that on that
particular theme. So
>> all right.
>> Um let me go ahead and read the spirit
of patience.
Uh, patience is another key attitude or
characteristic of the spirit necessary
to make an expert of holy war. Patience
is one's ability to persevere regardless
of surrounding obstacles and odds. The
Greek word hoop hoopo hoopon signifies
endurance.
Holy warriors will realize that theirs
is the battle of a lifetime.
They are by their vows of baptism sworn
to war against self self till death.
But because of the spirit of endurance
or patience is not mastered,
many tire and leave the ranks. For
others, patience seem as easy to lose as
one's keys.
>> We're told that patience is a result of
joy.
James 3:11 says, "Behold, we count them
happy which endure. You have heard of
the patience of Jo of Job and have seen
the end of the Lord, that the Lord is
very pitiful and tender and of tender
mercy." And again, Hebrews 12:2, looking
unto Jesus, the author and finisher of
our faith, who for the joy that was set
before him, endured the cross, despising
the shame, and is sat down at the right
hand of the throne of God.
In both these instances, the joy of the
Lord, the spirit of joy enabled
patience.
The moment we lose our joy is the moment
we lose our patience. Jesus endured for
us and grants us through his spirit the
same spirit of endurance. In receiving
the blessing of the spirit, we are also
to receive the blessing of endurance.
Blessed is a man that endureth
temptation. For when he is tried, he
shall receive the crown of life, which
the Lord has promised to them that love
him. We are commanded to endure, to
outlast temptation.
We are to be we are to be the ones left
standing in this holy war, not our sins.
The spirit of endurance empowers the
holy warrior with a no retreat, no
surrender mentality. He learns to endure
in the toughest of times, never throwing
in the towel. For the kingdom of heaven
is his battlecry. A person may possess
all the other attributes of the spirit,
but endurance determines how long you
possess them in any given trial or
hostile situation.
Therefore, the spirit of endurance or
patience becomes vital for without it,
we are at best sometime warriors.
James 1:8 says, "A double-minded man is
unstable in all his ways." The word
unstable means inconstant. It is
inconsistency that damages our witness
for Jesus. Our resolution with the
spirit of without the spirit of
patience, as powerful and as
well-meaning as they may be, are like
ropes of sand in the hand of temptation.
Therefore, it should be deemed of the
utmost importance to the warrior of
Christ that this spirit be mastered by
the grace
of God.
>> His grace is sufficient.
>> Yeah, his grace is sufficient.
>> So, there's a lot there. Mhm.
>> And I I would like to start off with the
thought of
patience being
the key
factor of every other fruit of the
spirit. And it's almost guys like as
we've been going through this through
this fruit we with each fruit it's
almost like without this these others
fail and this is why. Right.
>> Right.
Patience
>> because without joy,
>> right?
>> Patience can't.
>> But patience is how long your love
lasts,
>> patience is how long uh your joy lasts.
Patience is how long your peace lasts.
Right?
>> Patience is the endurance.
It is the lengthening, if you will, the
endurance of all the other fruits. So I
may have love but if I don't have
patience my love snaps like this right
>> my joy if I don't have patience at the
first you know sign of trial my joy
disappears
>> patience is the strength of all the
other fruits
>> right how long does your love last joy
last how long does your peace last
>> how long does your longsuffering last
because we can all have these
It's kind of like this last
>> um in when Samson is being desri
described as a powerful warrior, right?
The Bible says something interesting
about him. It says the spirit moved him
at times.
>> At times almost as if
>> the spirit he Well, it's not that the
spirit came would come and go. He would
>> he would take the spirit and be like the
spirit. Yeah. It's not like the spirit
was trying to [clears throat] move
>> and you can see that in his life, right?
>> You know, the spirit is using him
sometimes and other times it's like
Samson, what what are you doing? Right?
>> What are you doing?
>> We cannot afford to have the spirit move
us at times.
>> Meaning,
>> we must be able to endure in love,
endure in peace, endure in
longsuffering. And that's why Jesus
said, "He that endureth
>> to the end shall be saved."
>> So it's almost as if you guys, again, I
said it before,
every aspect, every fruit plays some
vital part
>> that makes all the other fruits
>> work.
>> Work.
>> Yeah.
>> But in some different aspect, right?
>> Yes.
>> The if you if you don't have patience,
but you have all these other fruits,
>> you have them, but it's sporadic. Mhm.
>> You're like a schizophrenic
spiritual Christian.
>> Hey man, I'm really happy. I hate you.
>> Unfort mercy.
>> Yeah.
>> Unfortunately,
it's a it's a lot of I won't say a lot
of a lot of us out there, but I'm saying
by God's grace, there's a lot
>> Yeah,
>> that's how we operate.
>> We should not
>> not to use this in a negative sense, but
it's like a bipolar spiritual bipolar,
right? Not not talking about
>> you're using the characteristics of
those
You're up and down. You're you're
happier. Oh, I love Jesus. Oh, man.
>> How how can we learn how to have that
endurance?
>> All right.
>> Yeah, I'm I'm glad you mentioned uh
Samson. You know, I really like this
particular chapter in the in the book on
patience because when you say the spirit
moved him at times, it reminds me of the
need to be disciplined and to remain
focused, you know. Um I I know that one
of my favorite verses dealing with
patience is Hebrews chap 6:12. It says
that you be not slothful but followers
of them who through faith and patience
inherit the promises. And so you know I
know there was a time when I always
thought that faith you know is just
blind faith but faith is not blind at
all. faith actually sees, you know, and
and the Bible says in Hebrews 11:24
about Moses that Moses endured as seeing
him who is invisible. So when I can keep
my eyes on that thing that gives me joy,
>> you know, and since joy is the thing
that allows me to be patient, if I can
keep my eyes on that invisible thing
through faith that that allows me to be
joyous and I'm not seeking my joy in the
world, I'm gonna be sometime if I'm
seeking it in the world because those
things don't last, right? Yeah. And so,
uh, for me, the art of war in this
particular section is saying, "Okay,
Terry, you've got to stay focused and
disciplined to keep your eye on that
thing that's producing this joy, and you
can endure."
>> The joy, the joy of the Lord is our
strength. And it was for the joy that
was set before him that he endured the
cross.
>> Amen. So, so he had to see that thing,
right?
>> Yeah.
>> Yes.
Yeah.
>> I have a question though.
>> What was the joy that Jesus had before
him so that he actually went ahead and
endured the cross? What was that?
>> So, go ahead. Go ahead, Terry.
>> I'm sorry. You and me. [laughter]
>> Oh, were you answering, Terry, or
>> Yes, he saw us.
>> Oh, yes. Okay. Yes. Yes. Yes. That's
what you said. You said you said
>> we we were the joy that was set before
him.
>> Yes.
>> H
>> we were the joy before him.
>> But if that if that was the joy for him
and he is our example, then shouldn't
our joy also be at least in part the joy
of winning other souls into God's
kingdom?
>> Oh yeah.
>> Hallelujah.
>> Oh yes.
>> Amen.
>> Absolutely. [clears throat]
Yes.
>> Um, you know, when
so we went on a uh on a family trip a
couple of months back and leading up to
that family trip, right? Everybody was
just like excited,
>> right?
>> You know, um Jesus
looked forward
>> to that family vacation that lasts
forever.
That joy that Jesus saw at the cross at
in Gethsemane was our salvation.
>> Amen.
>> And so when we're like, you know, when
your friends find out that you're going
to the same Oh, man. You're going to
come on a trip, too? Oh, man. That's
This is Wait, Michael's coming too. Oh,
wait. Cousin Nester's coming too. Oh,
and I mean, you know. Yeah. So you
that joy builds as you're like, "Wait,
that person's going to be there. That
person's going to be there. That
person's going to be there."
>> That joy of of seeing souls saved.
>> Yeah.
>> Um
that is what motivates us to have that
spirit of endurance, right?
>> Seeing us in heaven with Jesus, seeing
them in heaven with Jesus
>> is a very important Yeah. Go ahead.
>> Okay. I h So if that's our joy seeing
other souls in heaven like we have to
love these souls then in order to joyful
at the thought of their salvation. I'm
sorry I'm seeing this.
>> Okay. [laughter]
Absolutely.
>> It's love.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> And I think you said that Melinda on our
first Sabbath school that or maybe it
was Kazia actually. Um that love is the
>> Yeah.
>> foundational fruit.
>> Yep.
>> And from all of the others comes it
comes from love though.
>> So patience comes from love.
>> Yeah.
>> I mean there's what did it say that
Jesus talked about the commandment. He
said he was asked what is the greatest
commandment? And Jesus answered love the
Lord thy God with all thy heart and with
all thy soul and with all thy mind and
love thy neighbor as thyself. and these
two hang all the law and the prophets or
something like that. I don't know.
>> Yes, that that's it.
>> The one fruit of the spirit, love, is
like the foundation or I don't even know
if it's the foundation. It's from what
Jesus said, it sounds like it's like the
hook on the wall, you know.
>> Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes. On these
[clears throat] hang all the law and the
prophets. So love is the hook. I like
that.
>> Yes.
>> I like that.
>> Yeah. It supports
>> a hook supports and allows it to Yeah.
not fall.
>> Yeah.
>> Um endurance is a hard thing. You know,
if you think about running a race,
>> endurance takes
>> That's why I'm looking at people running
marathons. I'm like, I don't know how
you're pacing yourself like this.
>> Yeah.
>> Because I would just want to stop.
>> Go ahead. But they're pacing themselves.
And and endurance is the extended
exertion of something,
>> right?
>> Um whether you're
um
whether you're running, whether you are
>> um you know h having to hold a heavy
weight, right? It is something that is
stressing the body
>> and
requires
at least the desire
to
have that thing extended. So, if I'm
running a marathon, I need to learn
patience. My body's going to be under
some type of stress,
>> but I need to endure that stress, right?
Um,
>> we don't typically think of enduring
happiness,
>> right? Like I'm happy. How
>> can I endure this for too much longer
being happy?
>> I can't I can't stand it anymore.
>> Yeah. Endurance [laughter] is something
that that is required when the situation
is not comfortable.
>> Yes.
>> Right. And it can be simple, like I
said, from running a race to holding
something heavy, but it's something that
is challenging
>> that requires you to endure.
>> Yeah.
>> So, if we're talking about happiness
or joy,
having your joy tested
to endure means that there are things
around you that should make you sad,
>> should make you unhappy. M
>> endurance
is persevering
through that which is against you.
>> Right? So think about Jesus on the
cross.
>> Like he didn't die the death
that was instant,
right? He's on the cross
and the devil is tempting him the whole
time. Come down. Come down.
>> Which would be in essence, stop enduring
this,
>> right?
>> Why are you enduring this?
>> And just imagine being upon that cross.
>> He had patience through pain. He endured
>> patience through pain.
>> Through pain.
>> That's probably a a good way
to put it. Patience
>> through pain.
>> Through pain.
>> Uh how do we know how to endure? Go
ahead. Go ahead.
>> [clears throat]
>> Yeah, there's something you always say
in your sermons. We have not followed
cunningly devised fables.
>> And for me, you know, I' I've got to
have that thing that's real to me and
that motivates me in those times. That
thing that the Holy Spirit pops up and
reminds me of when I'm in the middle of
a trial.
>> That thing that pops up and the spirit
says, "Terry, remember this. Fight the
good fight of faith. Terry, remember
this. press on toward the mark for the I
need to have those spiritual realities
real to me. And so when I read like uh
Hebrews 11:13,
>> can I read this verse? This this verse
>> completely inspires me every time I read
it. It says, "These all died in faith,
not having received the promises, but
having seen them a far off and were
persuaded of them and embraced them and
confessed that they were strangers and
pilgrims on the earth." And every time I
read that, it seems like I get something
new out of it. And tonight when you
mentioned Samson, it reminded me, you
know, if I'm fighting for something
that's here, I'm gonna always lose my
patience, lose my faith, lose my lose my
cool and my meekness and gentleness
every time it feels like something's
threatening. Yeah.
>> But when I'm looking off into that thing
that no one can take and that no one can
touch, that joy that the world didn't
give me, but God did, I I can hold on
and endure if I can just keep my eyes on
that.
>> Yep. Absolutely.
>> And embrace that.
>> What does the Bible say? It says, "Set
your mind on things above, not on things
that are on this earth."
>> Yep.
>> Amen.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> Uh that uh
setting our minds on things that are
above,
beholding the joy that that was set
before Christ in that same way
>> um
>> enables us
to
endure
the things of this world,
>> right? They enable us
to go through trial. And Terry, I like
how you said, you know, not lose. I
think impatience.
When people say, "I got impatient," what
do they typically say? I lost it.
>> Yeah.
>> Right.
>> I lost it. Um, and that's what
impatience is. Impatience is losing
love. It's losing joy.
>> It's losing peace.
>> It's losing longsuffering. It's losing
gentleness.
>> And the devil's trying to get us to lose
it.
>> Right.
>> Amen.
>> And in losing it, we run the risk of
losing salvation.
>> So,
how do I hold on to the spirit
and not put it like this?
It's like our battle is to stay on the
cross.
>> Yes.
>> And Satan's battle
>> is to get us to come down.
>> Right. And so often we're like, you know
what? What did you just say to me? All
right. Hold on.
>> I'm take these nails out. I'mma come
down. [laughter] Face this situation
right now. Say, say it again. Say it to
my face. [laughter]
We come down.
>> And I was gonna say
>> we know how to get down.
Oh, that's [laughter] a certain time
right there. That's a
>> we know how to get down and Jesus never
got down.
>> Impatience is a result of stop. You
might be having faith and then when you
choose you choose
because it's getting hard not to have
faith any more then impatience is the
natural result of that
>> because pat not having faith um and or
let's say having faith and impatience
can't be in the in the same space like
when you're having faith in God like
you're just like faith is I can't see it
I'm trusting I'm enduring I'm waiting
You don't have to wait and be patient if
the thing is like right there in front
of you and you see it. But when you have
to have faith for in something, you have
to be patient. Yeah.
>> So when you're not when your faith is
not when you decide to like
[clears throat]
>> I'm just not going to believe in this
anymore. I'm just not going to believe
God's going to do this. That's when
impatience
>> Yeah.
>> will come in.
>> Yeah. Um
>> it has a place to plant it ugly seed.
>> Yep. Luke Luke 21:E 19.
>> In your patience, possess ye your souls.
>> Amen.
>> That's that's super significant because
>> what he's literally telling us is as
long as you have patience, you're going
to hold on. Possess
>> in your patience.
>> Possessing faith
>> possess your souls.
>> When we lose patience, we lose
possession of our souls. we lose
possession of our life.
>> The Bible speaks about here is the
patience of the saints, right?
>> Amen.
>> We're going to be called to go through a
time of trouble.
>> Endure a time of trouble.
>> And what that means
is a lot of people think of endurance in
the sense of all right, I got my food
stocked. I know I'm gonna go in the
mountains so I'll be able to endure.
>> I've been studying country living.
>> I'm gonna
>> That's not the endurance that's going to
save us. Right.
>> If we are not stocking up on the fruit
of the spirit,
>> we are going to found be found starving.
>> Yes.
>> In the country
>> and
right or wherever. Yeah. wherever you
are the I was just you know gonna say
that our these trials and things that we
go through now these are our little time
of troubles
>> to trust God have faith be patient see
how he works things out in our lives so
that when it comes to that it builds our
faith it builds our trust in God that
you know so for the next time you have
something to look back on,
>> to remember.
>> That's what Ellen White says that
children of Israel their um biggest sin
was they forgot.
>> And if we [clears throat] if we continue
to um have faith in God in our little
personal mini time of troubles, when we
get to
>> the real time of trouble, we will have a
whole memory bank of experiences with
God to be like, "God, this is hard. This
is the hardest thing I've had to endure
and trust you with, but I can have. But
you've always provided me
the patience and the strength and the
faith to be able to endure. So, you
believe like, "All right, God. I don't I
can't see.
>> I can I can see backwards what you did.
I can't see right now because what I'm
seeing in front of me is not it's not
it, but it's your back vision that helps
you."
>> Yeah.
>> Amen.
Amen.
>> Can I share a thought that um came to me
at work today? Um and first lady, you
kind of triggered it with what you just
said. Um, so usually when when I think
of having patience, not not all the
time, but I know a lot of us think,
well, it has to do with other people,
>> you know, [laughter]
>> other people other people require us to
have a lot of patience, right? Oh.
>> So, I'm thinking in the time of trouble
and every day, we always see things that
we might think are wrong, things that
are unfair, things that are unjust, you
know, uh things that we we would
probably define as, hey, you know,
that's that's evil
>> and that's bad.
>> And and we in our
even sometimes I want to say it's almost
sanctimonious self-righteousness. We
almost think that God, you just got to
do something and I need this dealt with
now. We need justice now. I want justice
now. I want this thing settled. I want
it resolved. I want it dealt with.
>> You know, and God gave me something
today that would re and God help me to
hold on to it because it was really
humbling for me to God says, "So, Terry,
what if it's you in the rebellion and
you in the wrong and you being wicked
and you being evil? How patient do you
want me to be then?" M
>> and so that same patience I want him to
have with me
>> when I need a little spiritual clucking
upside the head. I should want him to
have that same patient with somebody
else.
>> And so I've got to see me there needing
that patience.
>> Yeah.
>> I've got to see me there wanting God to
be longsuffering with me. Yeah.
>> And so that I that's I I'm praying about
that, working on that, but I want God to
help me really hold on to that because
>> yeah, I I want I want him to be patient
with me, but I should want that same
thing for someone else. So
>> Amen.
>> It does help me when I think about it
that way.
>> Amen.
>> Wow. Yeah. Amen.
>> Yes. I was just going to say, you know,
I always have to bring it home.
>> Make it
>> practical.
>> Very practical. that a lot of time our
little mini time of troubles
are right at home
[clears throat]
>> with our spouses, with our children,
with our family members, with our
siblings, with our even our parents, you
know, our friends,
>> the people that we know and that we're
closest to.
>> Um it's that's where our patience is
tried and tempted every day. Yeah. Um,
just even today I was I was ready to
start. I felt like you were being a
little slow. [laughter]
You weren't quite as on time as I And
usually I'm not actually honestly on
time, but um I was just like not feeling
very patient and I was like, man, we're
about to talk about patience and I'm not
having any patience right now. Um, but
>> that's just that's that's where it's at.
That's like um I don't know, we talk
about this um not trying to bring up
movies, but um you know, brush up, brush
down. Oh, karate, the first one.
>> You know, it's like he thought he wasn't
really being trained and he wanted to
learn how to fight, but he really was.
I'm saying I'm using this example to say
like when we're
>> in these little in our marriage or being
a parent and all those type of things
that's where we're learning at that
level on how to be patient because God
knows like bigger
much bigger issues are going to come
that you're going to need to be able to
exercise this and I'm trying to train
you now. So, we need to allow God
>> to train us and help us to be patient in
all situations
>> because if we don't master those things,
we're not going to master the big time
of trouble. This this is a little time
of trouble. Oh, my husband's being slow.
He's not on time [clears throat] right
now. Like, okay. So,
>> so that you know, you know what I'm
saying? Like I have to learn how to be
patient then
>> to be able to deal with
>> Satan coming with
>> greater temptations um
>> and and people wanting to threaten me
and put me in jail and why don't you
worship this way and
>> all of that like really?
>> Yeah. So in in the weightlifting world
um there's something called time under
tension. Mhm.
>> And time under tension is where you know
you if you're lifting a particular
weight um you don't want to just lift
that weight for like you know 10 seconds
and then okay I'm done. The longer
>> you can hold it slow.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So sometimes you slow your
motion down.
>> And the idea is like if you can do that
set
>> instead of in 10 seconds you're taking
30 seconds to do it,
>> 45 seconds to do it. a minute to do it.
What's happening is
>> the time under tension, that's what it's
called, time under tension. As that
increases, you're getting stronger.
>> It also and my trainer from like four or
five years ago, there's there's a
there's a brain that you're
>> there's a brain connection thing that's
happening and pathways that you're
building.
>> Yep.
>> When you do that.
>> Yep. And so you're actually getting
stronger. And when you're working with
this time under tension system,
>> you know, you stay at the same weight,
>> but you're trying to push the weight
longer.
>> Yeah.
>> So whereas before you were done in in in
20 seconds, now you were able to do it
for 35 seconds,
>> 40 seconds,
>> the muscle was able to endure it. Yep.
>> And it's getting stronger in its
endurance. Not like push it really
quick, but push it for 30 seconds,
you're getting stronger.
>> So
>> that makes sense.
That's how patient patience works,
right? It's time under tension.
>> How much time under tension can you
manage?
>> Jesus spent hours under tension at the
cross.
>> Oh, mercy.
>> That was time under tension.
>> Yes. Yes.
>> And for a lot of us,
>> our time under tension is like 10
seconds.
Why are you doing this to me? Time of
attention.
>> So, if we're like, "Okay, Lord, help me
to extend my tu uh tut, right? Time
under tension. Help me to expend my
expand my tutu.
>> Wow. Before it would take me it would
take someone three seconds to ri me up.
today. It actually took five minutes.
>> Five minutes before I lost it. But I
lasted five minutes.
>> Lord, please extend my time under
tension.
>> And before you know it, it's a day.
>> It's a week,
>> it's a month.
>> It's a year.
>> Your time under tension is growing.
>> And that's what we ought to be aiming
for, right? Lord, strengthen
increase my time under tension.
>> Amen.
>> Because when that happens, it is a sign
at the longer your time goes, it is a
sign that you're increasing in
>> you're getting stronger.
>> Yep.
>> Yeah.
>> You know, pastor, um,
in this chapter, you said you mentioned
Job. You've seen the patience of Job.
And obviously, we read about Job, right?
And it's it's beautiful to see it. And
um sometimes I think we kind of imagine
seeing ourselves in that in some of our
situation. But it's another thing to
watch someone uh under tension
>> and you can really be inspired by that,
you know, seeing someone go through it
and they still remain loving. They were
still remain calm. They still remain
composed. They still remain passionate
about ministry and doing what they do.
And um you know I I've watched you guys
I mean I you guys have been in ministry
>> 25 plus years
>> and I've watched you guys go and I know
you've gone through more than I've seen
but to stay passionate and to see the
fruit of living mana is actually the
fruit of you enduring your last season.
You know it's always better and better.
So I think the witness that that we give
when we stay patient, we inspire
somebody else because I certainly in
this season in my life have been
inspired by watching you guys. And so uh
>> again that's teaching me that hey
somebody's always looking and being
inspired or being discouraged.
>> Yeah.
>> You know by my
>> Yeah. You know Terry those are kind
words but honestly you inspire us. I
mean,
sometimes I just I hear what you say all
the time. You're like, "Oh, when I was
on vacation and I'm like, man, the faith
that you would have to have
for that long of long of a time and not
seeing things, you know, you talk about
how you were supposed to be out sooner
than I mean, you stayed in there longer
really, right? You were should have been
out sooner and you had to go through all
these different things.
you truly endured. He was strengthening
>> He was strengthening you and really for
a ministry outside of the vacation.
>> He that was your training.
>> You know, you guys you guys were
enduring while I was there. I was
watching you guys from there. [laughter]
So, I was seeing DVDs of pastor
ministering then. And so, uh
>> but he was preparing you to be to
minister to so many people.
>> Yeah.
>> Um
today like you do. And so yes, I just
wanted to say that too.
>> And you know, in that sense, time under
time under tension is never fun.
>> Time under tension is never fun, but it
strengthens you.
>> And this is why Jesus
>> allows us, you know, blessed is the man
that endureth
temptation.
>> Time under temptation.
>> T U T.
>> Yeah. time under temptation.
Lord, strengthen my tu time, right? Help
me to to endure because when I endure
this,
>> as as unpleasant as it is, I actually
come out stronger on the other end of
it,
>> right?
>> And um yeah, [clears throat]
time under time under tension is never
fun. No.
>> When you're
>> temptation under
>> Well, time
>> time under temptation. Yeah.
>> I'm just thinking like
>> that's that's what the cross was.
>> Time under temptation
>> because he was in physical pain. Jesus
was in physical pain. Yeah.
>> Spiritual emotional emotional pain
because he thought he was
>> he was separated from his father. That's
emotionally painful.
>> So physical and emotionally emotional
pain on the highest level. Mhm.
[clears throat]
>> He endured.
>> Yeah. He endured. So the text says,
>> literally says he endured the cross.
>> He endured it.
>> He endured the cross.
>> Like I said, we don't endure good
things.
>> Oh, you know,
>> get mad because somebody's late. Yeah.
He's endured a whole cross. Like we have
a lot of nerve.
>> We have a lot of nerve to be Yeah.
>> that way.
>> Yeah.
>> Wow.
That's such a powerful like thought to
me that that time under tension in
relation to the cross
>> and just like
>> wow he held it. You know that's Jesus
like mentioning the cross and he's just
like holding it
>> and he's not letting go. He's not
dropping the weight. He's not
>> he's not even getting shaky.
>> He's not getting
>> you know when the muscle gets tired. I
mean I'm sure
>> he was shaky. Well, when I say that,
>> you know what I'm saying? Like he this
was genuine.
>> It was genuine to it was genuinely hard
when I say shaky leg, but
>> mentally I don't believe he was ever
going to be like, "Yeah, you know what?
These people aren't really worth all
this."
>> He was never going to do that.
>> He had made up his mind to
>> to to go through it.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Now that
>> he probably was shaky, but no, go ahead.
I'm sorry, Terry. First of all, you just
said something right there, first lady.
I mean, I look at me and I can look at
my past and I can look at I mean, it
takes faith on a daily basis to to hold
it together, you know, by the grace of
God, but when you said that these these
people aren't really worth it. And then
he did it and I'm thinking you did that
for me.
>> I mean,
>> yeah.
>> Wow.
>> He did. And that that that that's why I
love beholding the cross when pastor did
that because
>> things like that pop out that you just
said and that makes me want to be better
and makes me want to endurance. It helps
me to say, "Okay, Lord, I'm holding on.
You know, I'm not going to give up."
>> Yeah.
>> I'm not going to give in. You didn't
come down for me. You didn't get down.
You know, you held on. So,
>> yeah.
>> He held on. He had made a decision.
>> It's something about
You've ever ever talked to somebody who
had been addicted to something and they
finally make a decision to stop
>> and yeah, they went through, you know,
cravings and different things like that,
but they made a decision. So, they were
mentally strong enough to overcome even
those
>> pings of cravings and those type of
things. A decision is so powerful. Same
thing when you when people are are have
have been um
>> very obese, like they just finally made
a decision.
>> I'm gonna stop. I'm going to do
something about this. I'm going to start
exercising maybe a few steps extra a day
or I'm just going to eat differently or
whatever. They've made the decision and
nothing can
>> turn them back,
>> right?
>> Yeah.
>> And Jesus made a decision
>> in heaven before [clears throat] he
came. Yep.
>> Like
>> like I'm going, father. I'm going.
>> Yeah. So when he tells us to pick up the
cross and follow him, um he is in
essence telling us, I'm trying to train
you with time with the time under
tension method,
>> right? Because picking up our cross,
that cross is heavy.
>> That's a heavy thing,
>> right? I got to endure the cross just
like he endured the cross.
>> Um,
so while I'm on the cross, I gotta still
love. While I'm on the cross, I got to
still say, "Father, forgive them. They
know what they know not what they do."
While I'm on the cross, I still have to
exhibit
>> the fruit of the spirit.
>> It's one thing to exhibit the fruit of
the spirit when you're off the cross.
It's something totally different to
exhibit the fruit of the spirit
with time under tension.
>> Oh man.
>> And he tells us to pick up we got to
take up the cross,
>> but it's not exactly his cross.
>> Him like him.
>> We can't take up his cross.
>> We can't take up his cross. And so the
>> his cross is he he bore the the sins of
the whole world. We got little crosses.
>> And we got little baby crosses.
>> Yeah. and he endured that whole cross in
the way that he did. So to be like,
look, your little baby crosses is
actually easy if you just trust me, have
faith in me, believe that.
>> Yeah.
>> Um my grace is enough. Your baby crosses
is nothing.
>> And because he did
>> He did that.
>> Yeah.
>> So much love.
>> Amen.
>> He just said, "Guys, I got you." It's
actually Satan likes to mess with our
mentals to be like it's so hard to serve
Jesus. It's so hard to surrender. You
know what I mean? Like he be messing
with you. Like
>> if you just like you know what? No, it's
right there.
>> Yeah.
>> I do the heavy lifting. Like he's our
spotter all the way. He's like I got you
like you. Let me
>> Yeah.
The the Holy Spirit is our spotter.
>> Spotter. [laughter]
We're doing gems analogies, but And and
you know it's it's it's interesting
because when you're when you're lifting
on with time under tension, you're
actually lifting to failure,
right? You're lifting to failure.
Meaning you're pushing a weight until
you absolutely cannot push it anymore.
Your muscle, you've torn that muscle up.
You can't if someone tried to give you a
million dollars to do one more rep, you
couldn't do it. So that's what it means
to to to lift a failure. And I think
>> for a million dollars, I bet you we'd
really, really try.
>> We'd really try. [laughter]
>> But it's almost like God is trying to
push us and extend our our time to
failure, right? So, if I'm failing at 15
seconds, come on. We We got to We got to
push your failure time
>> back so that you know, you're not
failing till 30 seconds, you're not
failing till 45 seconds, you're not
failing till a minute and 15 seconds.
And you keep trying to extend that
failure
>> so that your failure point when you
first started as a Christian your
failure point was
>> but as you grow in grace that failure
point gets pushed further and further
and further back
>> hopefully with the goal that the devil
can no longer find your failure point.
>> You know what I'm saying? Like
>> you're so imbued with the spirit of God
that the devil's looking for your
failure point and can't find it.
>> Amen.
>> Man, how long can you endure this?
>> As long as I have breath in me,
>> right? As long as the Lord is my
strength,
I'm going to endure.
>> Wow.
>> Amen.
Amen.
>> Yeah, this is actually exciting.
This is like when I say exciting like
we're all this is for all every single
human. This is available, you know, for
all of us. But
just to talk about it in in this way
like it's exciting and it's just like
you know people get excited about movies
and the superhero and
>> Jesus is the superhero and he's like
doing the like most amazing
>> feats like
>> it's the best
>> awesome saved us by God's grace movie
that we could ever imagine [laughter]
and we get to be we we get to play a
role But it's not it ain't no like we
don't get the super top roll like that's
his face. Y
>> he's just saving us.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> He's just saving us.
>> Amen.
>> Wow.
>> I We could go We're going to Well, we'll
pick up on this in two weeks because we
have
>> our amazing young people are they're
they're taking over. They're taking
over. We are excited. And I'm going to
say right now, they're even they they're
even taking over brother Terry's space.
They going they going to pray like him.
[laughter]
You got to pray as long as him now. You
guys have to pray as long as
>> No,
but and Melinda is actually going to be
preaching the sermon and so she is
taking Pastor Meyer's place. We are
excited to have our youth do our entire
church service next week. So please guys
be praying for them this week
>> and please be here and show up for them
next week because it's going to be a
blessing. The Holy Spirit
>> is really going to just
>> pour into them and use them. And so we
are excited. We are so excited. But with
that I didn't you guys I did a whole
little commercial.
>> No, please I hear [laughter] you. I want
to hear if you have any closing remarks
about patience.
Um, if you don't, that's I think one of
the things I want to say is that, yeah,
patience is difficult. I mean, we have a
saying in my household where it's like,
Lord, give me patience and give it to me
right now. [laughter]
>> It's a it's a hard thing to have,
>> but by the grace of God, our time under
temptation will expand until we can do
it
>> till, like Pastor Meer said, till our
last breath,
>> you know?
We follow our example, Jesus, who
endured his cross and we just have our
little tiny baby crosses. Yeah.
>> Baby crosses. Amen.
>> Amen.
>> Yeah. I like that, Linda. Thank you. I
just want to remember baby crosses. Get
up next tomorrow and
>> say, "Okay, Lord, let I'm focusing on
your cross because my cross is just a
baby cross and you just helped me carry
this little baby cross
>> and you just have so much more faith
because carry a big old hard cross.
Exactly. We ought to think about it this
way. Next to his cross, our crosses are
little twigs.
>> You know, little twigs.
>> Little twigs.
>> That's what they are.
>> Our little twigs cross. Melinda, you
just [snorts] said something and I, you
know, we kind of but it triggered a
thought in my mind and this will be my
closing thought is I don't know what you
just said, but it made me think of free
diving.
And uh free diving is where I believe
it's free diving where you like go down
without any gear and you're holding your
breath.
>> Ah,
>> and you know when people do that they
are always trying to break their record
of how long they could hold their
breath. Mhm.
>> And in a sense, this is what patience
is.
>> It's learning how to hold on to the
breath of God, right?
>> Learn learning how to hold the breath of
God and not exhale.
>> Learning how to hold that breath. And
you know, first I could only do it for
20 seconds. But
>> anything in which you're expanding your
time under tension,
>> that is teaching you,
>> all right, Lord, how long can I hold my
breath?
>> Right?
>> How long can I hold the spirit? Right?
the breath of the spirit in me
>> and not let it go.
>> Amen.
>> Physically, oh, I can only do that for,
you know,
[cough and clears throat]
20 seconds, a minute, what have you. But
spiritually, how long can I hold on to
the breath of God within me?
>> Help me to hold my breath. I've been
holding my breath
>> for six months.
>> Amen.
>> For a year.
>> Amen. for 10 years.
>> Amen.
>> Lord, help me to hold my breath and
never let it go.
>> Wow.
>> Amen.
>> So, yes.
>> Well, we are going to ask um
>> Wait, Terry, do you have a closing
thought?
>> I'm sorry, Terry. I thought I'm so
sorry. I thought you my I'm sorry,
Terry. Please go ahead.
>> Oh, no, no, no, no, no. I mean, I I I
love it and everything that's being
said. I I think pastors the thing pastor
said about even when you're on the
cross,
>> you got to have the fruit of the spirit.
Even when you're on the cross, you got
to love. Even when you're on the cross,
you know, and then taking that and
comparing it with Jesus's big cross and
my little cross. I mean, I can't be on
my little cross screaming at everybody,
you know. [laughter] I can't be on my
little cross being angry and mad on my
little cross. So, I really that gave a
that painted a really vivid picture for
me. You know, I'm there on the cross,
but I still need to have the fruit.
>> Yeah.
>> That's powerful.
>> Amen.
>> Well,
I'm gonna ask Melinda to pray
>> and close us out. Close us out today,
please, for Sabbath school. Um, yes. So,
yeah, if you would just please pray for
us.
>> Of course. Father in heaven, we thank
you so much for your ever abiding power
within us. Jesus, we want to thank you
for um your example on the cross that
you endured it for the joy that was set
out before you. We ask you that you give
us in this coming week strength to bear
our little crosses, Jesus. Please set
your Holy Spirit in our hearts and help
us to bear the fruits of the spirit even
while on the cross. And Lord, we ask you
to bless Pastor Meyers as he preaches
his sermon today. And um that you bless
the rest of the sermon and we thank you
for the Sabbath day. Amen.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> Amen.
>> Amen. So, yes, we um we're just Yeah,
that was just so powerful. Um just that
was just a powerful Sabbath school.
They're always really good. This has
been a blessing, though. And if you want
to get um if if you want to get the book
or the chapters, you need to go to
Mighty Networks. The book is called The
Christian Art of War. you go to mighty
networks and you're able we have the
four chapters that we've um been going
over so far there. So please uh get get
that so that you can be studying with us
and be commenting and sharing what you
have gotten from the book. So we
definitely you are a part of this
Sabbath school class and so I don't know
if you want to mention your sermon or if
you just want to say it's not what you
think.
>> Not what you think.
>> All right. So there it is.
>> Just go go with that routine.
>> Yes. It's not what you think. So yeah,
this is the time. Please invite
>> friends and family to church today. It's
so easy. It's so easy. Just say, "Hey,
join me. Here's the link. Click it." I I
don't think it's ever been that easy. So
yeah, definitely invite someone to
church uh at this time. And also like
and subscribe um the YouTube channel
that you are viewing from if you have
not done so. So we are just so happy
that you are here with us and want you
to continue to worship with us. We will
see you in church.
>> Amen.
[music]
Today, [music] our travels have brought
us here to the western Pacific Ocean to
explore the largest of the tiny islands
of Micronesia, the United [music] States
territory of Guam. This small island is
only 210 square miles, but it is filled
with incredible history, natural beauty,
and warm hospitality. [music]
>> [music]
>> Each night we've been sharing messages
of hope under the big white [music] tent
behind the Adventist clinic. Many have
been touched and blessed by the message
of the gospel as Jesus has been lifted
up night after night.
>> [music]
>> During our time here in Guang, we've not
only had the privilege of sharing the
gospel, but we've also been blessed to
experience [music] the gospel firsthand
through the hospitality of the people,
the beauty of the natural scenery,
[music] and the powerful lessons of its
history.
From this micro island of Guam comes a
macro [music] message of grace. This
tiny island was a battlefield during the
Second World War. Just one day after the
bombing of Pearl Harbor, Japanese forces
infiltrated [music] this US island
territory, sinking their vessels and
killing their marine and naval soldiers.
[music]
But six of the Navy Semen were able to
avoid capture by hiding in the jungle.
Tragically, five of them were recaptured
and brutally beheaded. But one of them,
US Navy Radman George Tweed, was able to
avoid capture and survive the entire 2
and a half years of Japanese occupation.
During that whole time, he was hunted
down until he was finally rescued in
1944. He was the final remnant that
remained when the war was finished. The
last US soldier standing when the dust
settled and the smoke cleared.
[music]
Now, besides the grace of God, there
were two practical things [music] that
enabled Tweed to survive his trying
ordeal. The Rocky Mountain forest that
provided a shelter for him to hide, and
the self-sacrificing kindness of [music]
the locals that provided him food to
eat. Now, one of those locals was
Antonio Artero. Tony hid Tweed on his
ranch property here on the northeast
portion [music] of the island. Each
week, Tony would bring food and water
and other supplies that Tweed needed.
Now, by doing so, he was risking his
life and the life of his whole family,
which included [music] his wife and
eight children that were with him. And
even though he knew the risk, he went
out of the way to save the life of
another. [music]
Today I was able to meet with Tony's
grandson, Dwight. He told me the story
and showed me the land where his
grandfather hid this [music] hunted
soldier. Dwight said that even though
his grandfather knew that it was a huge
risk, he couldn't turn Tweed down
because to him, [music] Tweed looked
just like Jesus with his long overgrown
facial hair. So saying no to him was
like saying no to Jesus. Being a very
devoted religious man, Tony felt that it
was his [music] spiritual duty to do all
he could to help and protect another in
need, even at the risk of his own life.
And that's [music] exactly what he did.
What an incredible story with so many
powerful lessons. You see, what happened
here in Micronia is a microcosm of the
macro grace of God. And as I've walked
upon the ground of this amazing war
story, here are some of the spiritual
lessons I was reminded of. First of all,
when the enemy hunts us down, the Lord
promises [music] to be our refuge. The
Psalmist said, "I'll lift up mine eyes
to the hills." Where does my help come
from? My help comes from the Lord who
made heaven and earth. Our God is our
refuge and [music] our strength, a very
present help in our time of trouble. And
here's another lesson. When we come
across someone that needs our help, like
Tony, we're [music] to be the hands and
feet of God to help and protect those
who cannot help and protect themselves.
And as we do, we are in reality
ministering to Jesus in the person
[music] of his children. For Jesus said,
"In so much as you've done it to the
least of these, my brethren, you've done
it also to me." And finally, just as
Tony unselfishly risked all to save
Tweed, Jesus indeed gave everything to
save us. When the enemy sought to take
our lives, Jesus laid down his in our
place. He suffered so that we might be
saved. He bled [music] so that we might
be blessed. He was forsaken that we
might be forgiven and [music] he died so
that we might live. That's what I call
amazing macro grace. It is macro grace
not only for [music] Micronia but for
the whole world, for you and for me. It
is offered to all who feel themselves
insignificant [music] and small. To all
whose backs are against the enemy's wall
and to all who are burdened with [music]
the guilt and the shame of a moral
fault. It is this macro grace that will
lift us up from our fall. will give us
the spiritual strength [music] to stand
tall and it will protect us like a solid
rock wall. And in order [music] for this
macro grace to be ours, all we have to
do is call. And so today, I appeal to
you to call upon the God of macro grace
right now and you shall be saved.
[music]
>> [music]
>> Heat.
Heat.
Heat. Heat.
[music]
Heat.
Welcome back, Living Mana Church family.
We're so happy that you've decided to
continue to worship with us today. We
are so thankful that you are here on
this Sabbath day. It's a blessing to
have all of you. Please put in the chat
where you are viewing from. And if this
is your very first time, put a one in
the chat because we want to say a very
special welcome to you. We know we have
viewership from all around the world.
Literally all around the world. And uh
we'll have to go back and see if we've
if there's any country that we haven't
had somebody say, "Hey, I'm from this
place and I'm here at Living Man Church
uh worshiping with you today." We have
had probably not every single country in
the world, but many countries in the
world. I'm I'm positive every continent
has been visited from, but I don't know
about every single country. So, but at
some point it is our goal. It is our
prayer that we will get there. So, we
are just thankful to have all of you
here watching from all around the world
and all around America as well. It is
just such a blessing again to have each
and every uh person here with Living
Mana Church. I just want to tell you
right off the bat for our um one those
who are putting a one in the chat right
now just to let you know that we are a
completely online church international
church and we have programming all
throughout the week. We have programming
on mental health that's on Mondays. We
have programming on physical health and
that's true health Tuesdays. We have two
prayer services on Wednesday. We have
young adult programming by our young
adult uh pastor Lil Ammy Richardson. And
so we are here all throughout the week.
We have small groups that meet all
throughout the week. And so pretty soon
I'm going to show you and share with you
how you can u become a part of that. But
we just want you to know that we have
something here for you at Living Manage
Church again all throughout the week.
And with that said, I want to just
remind everyone because I am one of the
hosts for Mental Health Mondays, myself
and Dr. Ricardo White. And we will be
back this Monday. We missed last Monday,
but we will be back this Monday. We are
continuing our conversation about
marriage and relationships. Even for
singles, everybody is bringing their
questions and we are answering them. And
you guys have a lot of questions. So,
just want you to let you know. Please
check us out Monday at 700 p.m. Central
time and we are talking about everything
marriage, relationship, and being
single. You don't want to miss that. So,
for those of you um who are just joining
us for the first time, or maybe you
haven't done so yet, I want to show you
how you can stay connected to Living
Mana Church and you will be able to stay
connected to get text alerts. And so,
Ellen, it's very simple. You can see
there it says Loc text. You can text Loc
8552074107.
If you are here in North America, you
will receive these texts to help to
remind you of all the things that I just
mentioned because we have so much going
on during the week. And you know, right
now you might have thought, "Oh, Atante
just mentioned that. I want to attend
that or I want to try to get involved in
a a small group or something or prayer
something and um you will say that now
but during the week you will forget
because life is always lifeing and it's
very busy. So that's what these text
alerts do. They help to remind you that
LOC is going live and it is very
helpful. So that's if you are here in
North America. If you are viewing from
outside of North America, you will not
be able to receive those texts. But if
you sign up for Mighty Network, you will
then get this notification and
information through Mighty Network. Now,
even if you are here in America, you
still want to sign up for Mighty Network
because that is our virtual home. That's
where you will learn about all of our
small groups. That's where you we form
community here at Living Mounted Church.
You will meet the church. You will meet
the leaders of uh different small groups
and you will meet other church members
as well and get to know everybody a
little bit better there on mighty
network. So right now in the chat there
is a link. So if you have not signed up
for mighty network yet, please click on
that link and sign up so that you can be
getting all the information and you will
not be missing any information that's
happening. what's going on here at
Living Mana Church. So, please click
that link. We also just want to remind
you guys that we do have LMOC
uh kids. We have um their own
programming and that is 11:30 central
time and you can text kids to 8552074107
or you can email locoscidana.urch
and the leadership will get back with
you to tell you how you can get your
kids signed up for LMOC kids. So if you
have kids, grandkids, nieces, nephews,
friends, kids, let them know that we
have LMC kids and give them the
information that you see on your screen
so that they can get involved in LOC
kids. Want to remind you all that Pastor
Meyers does have virtual church office
hours and you can see there how you can
uh get an appointment. um you would
schedule that with our secretary Patrice
at living.live
and um she will get that scheduled for
you. She'll respond and you guys will
figure out what time works for you and
Pastor Myers and that will be scheduled.
Also, just want to let you guys know how
you can become a member if you are
interested of living mana church. There
are three different ways. And that email
that you see on your screen again, the
patrice living.live, that is the email
you want to use for membership. If you
are a 7th Day Adventist um member and
you want to transfer your membership,
you can go through the process and
request a membership transfer. If you
are not a Seventh Day Adventist, but you
um are studying the truths in the Bible
and you want to become a Seventh Day
Adventist, you can become um a member
through profession of faith. So, you
don't have to get rebaptized because
you've been baptized and you don't feel
like that's what you're needing, but
you're uh just wanting to join by
profession of faith, you can do that and
you can email Patrice if you're
interested in that. And then finally, if
you just if you want to physically get
baptized by Pastor Meyers, you can also
uh start that process by emailing
Patrice Livingmana.live and Pastor
Meyers will be the one that baptizes
you. So, if that is your desire, please
use that email and those are the three
ways that you can become a member here
at Living Mana Church. I am so excited
to announce that um yes true health
Tuesday we are having that but I was
wanting to announce before I do that for
the youth Sabbath I'm sorry the it's not
Sabbath school there is the youth the
youth are doing our church service next
week and so um I don't know if that
slide is there okay it's not going to be
a slide I am just going to tell you
about it so it is the first uh youth
Sabbath. Our youth are going to take
over Living Mana Church. That's right.
We are passing the baton next Sabbath to
our young adults, our youth. And we know
that they're going to do an amazing job.
So, when I say it's youth Sabbath, they
are doing Sabbath school. They are doing
the prayer service. They are doing the
sermon. And we are so excited. the young
lady that you saw this morning doing
Sabbath school with us, Melinda, she
will be doing uh the divine worship
sermon and uh the youth will be doing
like a round table what you see us doing
for Sabbath school and they will also be
doing prayer uh just like uh brother
Terry and sister Amber do. So we are
excited and I want you to pray for them
and pray this week that the Holy Spirit
will use them powerfully. Please invite
your youth uh that are going to be
watching to watch our youth lead out in
prayer next week uh for Sabbath. So,
we're very excited about that. But
please keep them um in your prayers.
There it is. Yes, the speaker is
Melinda. Um and you can uh just share
uh you can share this with as many so
many we want so many people to hear and
to see how God is going to use them. um
next week and what God has put on their
heart to share with all of us and to
minister to us. So we are very very
excited about that. Okay, we now we have
True Health Tuesday which which is
amazing with Dr. uh Maria Humel. She is
talking about nutrition and the brain.
It's groundbreaking series um by Dr. um
Humel. And let's see here. All right.
Yes. So, it is uh by Dr. Maria and that
explores the powerful connection between
what we eat and how we think, feel, and
function. I always say if you put
garbage in, it's going to be garbage
out. So, it definitely affects our mood
and and all of those things. So, for
mood regulation to memory, Dr. Hume
unpacks the science behind the food as
as fuel for for mental clarity and
emotional uh resilience. Whether you're
turning in for the or sorry whether
you're tuning in for the first time or
continuing the journey, this isn't your
average health talk. It's a revelation.
Each installment offers fresh insight
into how nutrition shapes the mind,
making it essential viewing for everyone
seeking a sharper and more balanced
life. Uh, this will be streamed on
Tuesday, 700 p.m. Central time on ElC.
Your brain will thank you. Remember to
subscribe uh to our channel and sign up
for text messages so you don't forget.
Guys, this is powerful information that
you're learning. So you definitely don't
take it for granted that you know what
this is stuff people pay for. And here
at Living Manage Church, we like to
bring you the best quality information
and programming and you can just tune in
for free and you can watch it and
re-watch it as many times as you would
like. And please share with your family,
friends, and others.
We also know about Hurricane Melissa and
how it impacted Jamaica. If you are
wanting to be um a part of the relief um
from Melissa, you can um help ADRA
respond um and and um Hurricane Melissa
has uh left communities devastated um
home destroyed, families displaced, and
basic needs unmet. In moments like
these, address steps into it steps in to
deliver emergency aid, clean water,
food, and shelter to those most
affected. But they can't do it alone.
Your donation empowers ADRA to act
swiftly and compassionately, bringing
hope and practical help to survivors.
Every gift, large and small, makes a
difference and restoring lives. Your
donation empowers Adra to act swiftly
again and compassionately. Um if you uh
want to be the hands and feet of Jesus,
you can text hurricane to 8552074107
to receive the information on how to
donate. Again, the number is there on
your screen if you would like to help in
the relief from Hurricane Melissa.
Want to also remind you guys about a
ministry that we have here at Living
Mana Church called Give Mana. Give Mana
is more uh than a ministry. It is our
front line of outreach, compassion, and
practical help. Whether it's food,
prayer, resources, or connection, Give
Mana is actively meeting needs and
making faith visible in real time. If
you're looking to get involved or if you
need support in your local community,
this is where the mission meets the
moment to serve and be served. Reach out
to Sister Shaun Wright. She's ready to
connect you with the heart of this
movement. Let's be hands and feet. Let's
give mana.
So, um, that's definitely a powerful
ministry that was started here at Living
Mana Church. So, if you're wanting to
get involved, you can text Mana to that
855 number and you will be able to get
involved. Also, just want to thank all
of you for what you uh do by supporting
Living Managed Church and your faithful
giving. We are three and a half years
old, almost four years old. And so I
just want to remind you on how you are
able to give and to support Living Mana
Church and the worldwide 7th Day
Adventist Church. So as you can see
there on your screen, you can go to
adventistgiving.org or and there you
will click in the top right hand corner
and uh it'll ask you to where you want
to give and you put in Living Manurch
and then a virtual tithe envelope will
drop down and you can see there that
you're able to give your tithe which
goes to the Northeastern Conference and
Living Mana Church is a part of that
conference. You can give to the local
church budget. That is what we that's
what stays here with Living Mana Church
so that we can do all the many things
that Living Mana Church is doing to keep
our equipment updated and so that we can
broadcast broadcast in the best quality.
We there's also a place where you can
give to the benevolence fund which is
there so we can help others who are in
need and you will see so many other
areas that you can give. If you are not
wanting to give online and you'd like to
mail in your tithe and offering, you can
do that by using the address that's on
your screen, P. Box 428, Owens
Crossroads, Alabama 35763.
And when you do that, please just put um
a little note, send a little note with
it so we can know exactly uh how much is
for tithe, for offering, and exactly
where you want um your giving to go. And
so again, we just want to say thank you.
Thank you for your faithfulness, your
continued giving, your prayers, your t
sharing living mana programs, inviting
friends and family to church. you are
working with God in helping spread this
gospel and spreading uh the knowledge
and awareness that Living Man Church is
here and what we offer and what God um
has given us to give to you. And so we
just thank you uh just for all of your
faithfulness, faithfulness and
consistency. Uh we just want to just
lift up a prayer of thanksgiving to God
at this time. So if you would just bow
your heads with me as we pray.
Heavenly Father, Lord, I want to thank
you for being an amazing God, a faithful
God, a God that um like we were learning
in Sabbath school, Lord. A God that your
grace is truly enough. It is sufficient
for us and it will help us carry our
baby crosses. Lord Jesus, you were able
to endure such a huge cross on our
behalf and you say, "Follow me and carry
your cross, but our cross is nothing
compared to your cross." And you give us
the strength, more than enough strength
that is needed to carry our crosses,
Lord. And we thank you. We praise you
for that, Lord. I just want to lift
everyone up that is um listening to this
program right now, whether it's live or
if it's later later on. They're watching
it later. Lord, I just want to lift I
don't know them. I don't know everyone
who's watching. I don't know their
situation. I don't know their problems,
but Lord, you do. You know the burden on
their heart. You know what they are
needing today. And so, I am praying that
you will answer that prayer and provide
that for them. I pray the message that
Pastor Meyers is going to deliver today
will be the message that they
specifically needed to hear to touch
their hearts and to change their lives.
Lord, I ask that you be with him, that
your Holy Spirit be with him as he
speaks to all of us. And again, that it
will touch all of our hearts and we will
leave changed. We ask all of these
things in Jesus' name. Amen.
We didn't want to make this video, but
it's time we [music] said something.
The church isn't perfect.
We're all broken, and we all fall short
more [music] often than we'd like to
admit. The painful reality is that
sometimes our brokenness [music] hurts
those around us.
Some of you here today have been wounded
by the church
through an experience, a
misunderstanding, [music]
or the actions of someone you trusted.
For that, [music] we want to say how
deeply sorry we are. Your pain matters,
and we hurt with you.
Today, we [music] want you to hear this
clearly. You are not alone.
Where people [music] have caused hurt,
God offers healing. Both for you and for
the church. Where there has been
division, [music] God brings unity.
Where people have failed, God remains
[music] faithful.
We want you to know that you belong here
and are deeply [music] loved.
And we will walk this journey with you.
As a [music] church, we're committed to
healing, reconciliation,
and unity.
If you need someone to talk to, we're
here and we're ready [music] to listen.
[music]
>> [music]
>> You [music] are here
moving [singing]
in our midst.
I worship [music] you.
I worship you. [singing]
>> [music]
>> You are here
working in this place. [singing]
[music]
I worship you.
I worship [singing]
you.
[music]
You are here
touching every heart.
[singing and music]
I worship you.
I worship [singing] you.
>> [music]
>> You are here
healing [singing] every heart. [music]
I worship you. [music]
I worship you
cuz you are way [music] maker, miracle
[singing] worker, promise keeper, light
in the darkness. My God, that is
[singing] who you are.
>> [music]
>> Oh, you are way maker,
[music and singing] miracle worker,
promise keeper, light in the darkness.
My God, that is who you
[music and singing] are.
You are here.
Turn lives around. [music]
I worship you.
I worship [singing] you.
You are here [music]
[singing] in every heart.
I worship you. [music]
I worship [singing]
you.
You are way maker, [music and singing]
miracle worker, promise keeper, light in
the darkness. [singing] My God, that is
who you are. [music]
Oh, [singing] you are way maker, miracle
worker, [music] promise keeper,
[singing] light in the darkness. My God.
That is who you [singing] are.
That is who you [music] are.
That is who you are.
That is [music] who you are.
Even [music] when I don't see it, you're
[singing] working. Even when I don't
feel it, [music] you're working. You
never stop. You never stop working. You
never stop. You never
[music and singing] stop working. Even
when I don't see it, you're working.
Even when I don't feel it, you're
working.
>> [music]
>> You never stop. You never stop working.
You never stop. You [music] never stop
[singing] working. Even when I don't see
you working. [music] Even when [singing]
I don't feel it, you're working. You
never stop. You never stop working.
[music]
You never stop. You never [singing] stop
working. Even when I don't [music] see
you working. Even when I don't feel it,
you're working. [music]
You never stop. You never stop working.
You never stop.
Cuz you are way [music] maker, miracle
worker, promise keeper, light in the
darkness. My God, [singing] that is who
you are.
>> [music]
>> You are way maker, miracle worker,
promise keeper, light in the darkness.
My [music and singing] God, that is who
you are.
That [singing] is who you are.
That is [music] who you are.
>> That is who you are.
>> That is who you [singing] are.
Sing wide all ye heavens.
Let the [music] praise go up as the
walls [singing] come down all creation.
>> Here at [music] Living Mana, we bear
each other's burdens. When you need
support or prayer, when you're feeling
[music] discouraged
or alone or anxious,
you don't have to face life struggles
alone.
Heat. Heat.
>> [music]
>> Let us come boldly unto the throne of
grace that we may [music] obtain mercy
and find grace to help in our time of
need.
The Lord is close to the brokenhearted
and saves [music] those who are crushed
in spirit.
Greetings saints of the most high God.
Happy Sabbath. Welcome to another
edition of Living Matterners Prayer and
Praise Time. I am brother Terry here
with my lovely bride Amra as always and
uh want to just say we are happy to be
here with you all. God bless you. I was
putting in the chat earlier. You know
what it it just never gets old. And uh
we thank God for the word. We thank God
for you. And uh we're just giving praise
today.
>> Amen.
Are we starting right off in pray praise
reports?
>> No. Uh I just wondered if there was
something you might wanted to say. So,
but
>> Okay. I thought, you know, maybe you
wanted to do your roll call or
>> I'm going to do that roll call in just a
minute. But you know what? I actually
got distracted. I just heard a fire
truck a big old horn blew and I was
like, "Let me reather here, pass it off
to her, but she threw it right back."
So,
>> sorry.
>> That's all right.
>> Hi, Katie. Hi, Ayana. We see you in the
chat. Thank you so much for greetings.
Greetings everyone. Love y'all. Amen.
Amen. Listen, um I was speaking with
Pastor Tante earlier and and and they
really reminded me that we really want
to pray about uh you know, you've heard
all everyone's heard about the
government shutdown and stuff and and
we've obviously heard about people
who've been affected by it and we've
been praying for those people you know
who've been uh you know dealing with you
know some of the financial strain of it.
but it's actually possibly could affect
living mana with the flights being
delayed and the flights being cancelled
because we're having baptisms next week.
And so we want to pray and keep that in
our prayers. God uh open up the door and
that the gospel not be hindered by some
of the things that are going on. So
we're continuing to pray about that. I
also wanted to send a special shout out
to Sister Charlotte. We thank God for
you and that your surgery went well and
that you're healing up and they found
those pain uh key points and then
dealing with that stuff and some of your
soreness has decreased. So we're happy
to hear that. Sister Charlotte.
>> Amen.
>> Amen. Amen. Um I saw somebody ourable
from Lima, Peru wanted to shout you out
all the way from Lima, Peru. God bless
you. Welcome to Living Mana. Nice loving
warm welcome to all of you. I see some
folks in the chat.
>> I see. Blessing Laya. 62 retired.
>> Okay. 62 retired. I think I recall you
from Power Wednesday. Yes, we were
praying. Love you. Thank you for being
here with us today. We love you. Good
good uh uh happy Sabbath to you and good
day to you.
>> Hello Joanne.
>> Okay. So,
>> MO105
A9R. Not sure. Is that Majesca? I'm not
sure. it. It's Majesa. I see her tag
there on the side. Okay.
>> Hello, Sister Majesa. Love [laughter]
you. Love you. Amen.
>> Hello, Artell.
>> Some of you may be knowing that your
name tags are coming up different on
YouTube for some reason. Even mine was a
little bit different when I
>> But but I recognize you because you're
family and uh we can recognize your
picture on the side of it.
>> Yes.
>> So, just anyway, um roll call. Sister
Devil Deborah Schwart uh from the
Netherlands. I saw you my beloved
sister. Uh good to see you here with us
today. Uh John Heasley, brother Reed,
Sister Pauline Show Good Eye, my beloved
big sister. Uh love you all the way.
Amen. And uh brother Elco and um brother
brother Danny, sister Jackie, love
y'all. Roll call. Janney, she already
mentioned Laya. Laya Laya Peterson, not
Leela, it's Laya. And Joanne Dawn
Washington, God bless you, my sister.
See you there. Nerki, Marcela Johnson,
Seb Grace, I saw you in the chat
earlier. Thank you so much. And uh
Shironda Donahue, that was a powerful
text you put in earlier about the love
of God. So shouting you out, my love.
Oh, uh Annette Rivas, my beloved sister.
Good seeing you. Bless you and your
family. We love you.
>> I also see Leon. Leon,
>> I'm getting to my brother.
>> We're still waiting for you to come
visit us, Leon.
>> Yes, brother Leon. Brother Leon Ryland.
>> [laughter]
>> Amen. Brother Jose Bos from Bakersville.
Welcome to Living Mana today. Nice. Uh
healthy for sales. Healthy sales for I'm
not sure who that is, but happy Sabbath
and welcome. Yobi 7485Z. We saw you in
the chat. Sister Jodie, our beloved
sister Jodie from Canada. We we love you
and thank you so for being with us today
as always. Sister Zadwa.
>> Oh, and Sister Shaunin's in the chat.
Sister Shaunine uh we were praying about
the possible flights being shut down and
Sister Shaun shared a wonderful idea and
I believe she may have gotten it from
our beloved sister Denise Richardson
that perhap there are deals uh on uh
with uh uh bus lines and train lines. So
that that's another way to travel. You
know it's going to be a little bit
longer ain't going to be as quick as
flying but the bus lines and the there
there are sales going there are deals
right now. So you get some discount
stuff going on. And I don't have links
to share, but we will get that up
somewhere that if you if you're
traveling and you need to travel and you
and you run across a flight that may be
cancelled, a possibility of a canceled
flight, uh you can try the bus or the
train. And uh so there's a thought.
Thank you for that, Sister Shaun and
Sister Denise.
>> And hello, Elco.
>> Yes, me and Brother Elco. Brother Elco
hosted the um huddle this morning and we
had some wonderful fellowship and
conversation and devotion. And also want
to ask you to join us for the afterlow
today. Uh brother Danny and sister
Jackie will be hosting. We're getting
ready for a very powerful message. Want
you to buckle up. We'll be praying about
that in just a moment when our special
guest comes on to lead us in
intercessory prayer. But so that's all
we have for now and we're going to go to
the prayer uh praise reports. But I did
just want to share our hearts with you
and say we love y'all again. Thank y'all
for your prayers. Prayers are so
powerful. I mean, I put a prayer. We had
our 24-hour prayer and fasting
yesterday. And I put a request in that
chat. Oh, love you too, Sister Jackie.
Love you, my beloved sister. Man, and
praying for you, my beloved sister. God
will move. I put a prayer request in the
chat yesterday. And before I could close
the phone good and get it in my pocket,
God was already answering. I I'm not
going to talk about it right now. I know
Amber might, but I don't. I want to say
God is good and he will answer on time.
Saints, hold on. Don't give up. It was
fast. That was a fast fast prayer prayer
request that was answered.
>> Yes. Yes. And even if your prayers are
not answered speedily, believe me, he's
we we have a song we should sing in the
south. He's an ontime God. Yes, he is.
Might not come when you want him, but
he'll be there right on time.
>> He got to orchestrate stuff in his own
perfect time.
>> Yeah, he's an ontime God. I feel like
singing that thing right now, but praise
God for [laughter] that. Hallelujah.
>> All right. Well, I do have some
announcements um before we go into the
praise reports. Just a reminder to
submit your prayer requests and praise
reports to the email address
praymmanana.urch.
We're especially asking that you submit
those this week for our young adult
Sabbath next week so that they can um
share praise reports with you. Um, we're
excited that they'll be taking over our
prayer and praise time as well. So,
don't forget to support the young adults
next week.
>> Looking forward to that. That's going to
be fun.
>> Yes. Yes. And also, if you would like to
join us in the prayer team or join a
special ops prayer team under the prayer
team umbrella, please also send an email
to praymanana.urch.
church. If you need to request a special
ops prayer team for yourself or a loved
one, please send an email to spec ops.
That's spc ops at livingmana.urch.
If you need a midweek pickup, you have
two opportunities. one with power
Wednesday that occurs every Wednesday at
4:30 p.m. Pacific Standard Time, 6:30
Central and 7:30 Eastern time. And we
have an amazing time at Power Wednesday.
It is not just prayer. We either have a
devotional or someone shares a powerful
testimony of how God has moved in their
life. Um, but it's a it's a time that we
can reflect and just spend time with God
in prayer. Amen.
>> And each other. We also have the power
line going on every Wednesday right
after power Wednesday live on YouTube.
And that is uh where we take live prayer
requests. And that is one of our
evangelistic tools. Um please invite all
your friends and family. It doesn't
matter what denomination or anything. We
invite all those um to join the power
line
for live prayer.
>> Amen. If you would like to join the
women's ministry on Mighty Networks,
please send an email to
womenlivingmana.urch.
And finally, if you would like to join
the men's ministry, they have changed
their email address to men living.
And oh, one last, we got lots of
announcements today, folks. [laughter]
[gasps]
If you uh didn't know, LMOC has a
Facebook page. So, we are trying to
drive some um attention to the living
mana Facebook page so that you can um
join us in the chat. Well, not the chat,
but comment, share,
get it out there. So, that is another
way that we are reaching out to people.
You can find that on Facebook by
searching my living mana.
>> Amen. Just want to do this real quick. I
see uh Shironda
Donahghue. Yes. Yes. I was s I saw you
Shirana. Shirana Donahghue. Much love to
you too. I saw the loving hands there.
And listen, we're talking about an
ontime God. I saw my sister in the chat.
Sister Valerie Lambert, you are
watching. We love you. Sister Val,
everybody sending love out to you. Uh
hold on and be strong. Sister Val, you
are such an inspiration to us. Love you.
Genuinely love you with the love of the
Lord. And I pray you feel that from our
hearts today. I saw you in the chat,
Sister Val.
>> And I see money P6026.
Much love to you. Thank you for
>> Yes. And brother Jason Diggs, uh we see
we will definitely remember you and your
family uh to pray for you today if
you're watching, my brother. Amen. I saw
you there in the chat. Love you, Sister
Valerie. I had to come back one more
time. Much love to you. Hold on and be
strong, sis.
>> Yes,
>> I did catch a couple of praise reports
in the chat live today. So, I did want
to read a couple of those before I go
into the ones that um were submitted. I
am Rain. Praise report. God saved us
from a very dangerous situation. 5
minutes after we got off the freeway
going 70 miles per hour, our front drive
driver tire went flat in a few seconds.
Thank you, Lord. And we praise God that
you are okay.
>> Who put that in?
>> I am Rain.
>> Praise God for you. Thank you for
sharing that. Thank God for taking care
of you.
>> SB King 8005.
Whoever prayed for me last week with my
cursing, thank you. was shocked that the
entire week my cursing went down like
below 10%. My cursit cursing is usually
well over 100% daily and I was beyond
shocked. Well, I think we can all relate
to that.
>> We all [laughter] need
Hallelujah. Listen, if there was ever a
time that we ought to come together and
just give God some praise for a praise,
that's a praise report right there and
y'all know it.
>> Yeah. I quit I quit cursing. I think I
was 30 and I was just joining
um a young uh a youth ministry and I was
newly Christian and Terry used to be a
sailor in the Navy, but I sure swore
like a senior like a sailor in my past.
So I
>> praise God for removing that.
>> You know, we we want to kind of chuckle
about it, but it's serious. And I want I
I want to say thank God for you because
I I know that, you know, uh when I first
went on vacation, you know, and I and I
gave my life to the Lord on July 24,
1992, and I remember
uh Lord, I cannot get this stuff out of
my mouth, right? And it was just coming
out. So, I I had this little thing where
I put down marks every time I'd say
something I shouldn't have said, I'd
have to do push-ups. Well, I was going
to end up looking like the incredible
hug after a while [laughter] because I
just couldn't stop. Right? So, I said,
"Well, look, I might as well just shut
up. Don't talk." Right? And then the
Lord showed me something. He says,
"Look, don't focus on the darkness.
Focus on the light." Amen. And I began
to put the word of God in. And the next
thing I knew, I don't know where it
went. The word of God, listen, the
darkness cannot abide in the light.
Listen, when you go into your room at
night and it's dark in there, you ain't
got to gather up all the darkness and
set it out there. Just turn the light
on. It's got to go somewhere. And so,
thank God for you, beloved, sharing
that. That that's a beautiful praise
report.
>> Yeah, we love that. And so relatable.
>> Okay. From Hope,
>> I just want to give an update on my
health. God has taken my pneumonia from
me and I'm healed. Thanks. Thank the
team so much for their prayers.
>> Amen.
>> And I think Terry shared Charlotte
Stanforth's uh praise report. The
procedure on my back is healing and the
offending pain sites
seem to have been accurately pinpointed.
The soreness is greatly reduced. Thank
you for your prayers.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> From Katie S2067.
I finally got a job. Praise God. Please
pray that everything goes smoothly and
that I perform well. We will absolutely
pray for that. Please also pray for my
health and my mother's health.
Congratulations, Katie, on your new job.
Um, I caught this in the chat last week
right after our segment was over from
Barbara Fickru 3394.
Um, the prayer for my son Mark's third
interview was successful. He completed
his first week on his new job. Thank you
everyone for your prayers.
>> Praise God. And finally, Nicole Curtis.
Nicole sent Terry and I a group text
last week during Sabbath,
>> and she says, "Sorry to text y'all
during service, but that song they
played today got me." And the song they
played that s last Sabbath was the one
about God who governs angel armies shall
place encampments around me. Whom shall
I fear?
>> Hallelujah. So,
>> what a song.
>> The night before Halloween,
I was renting a desk at this co-working
office space. Long story short, on
Thursday night, I was at this space
after hours giving my ministry
presentation for El Moses on Zoom. While
I'm sharing and listening to others
share in the common area of this
co-working space, there was a group of
ladies meeting. They had booked that
area for the night. Well, I could hear
them. Turns out they were witches,
Wiccan followers, and they were doing
incantations and spells. I am hearing
this while I'm listening to ministry
proposals. But God, he kept me and
protected me. I prayed for these ladies
to be delivered from the deception they
are under and kept on focusing on Jesus.
And like the song lyrics that played
last Sabbath, the God who governs angel
armies shall put encampments around me.
Whom shall I fear?
>> My my my
>> Oh, that just gave me some goosebumps.
>> Look, I was thinking while you were
reading that thing, you know, I I know I
don't have no hair to be standing up on
my head, right? But every time I think
about that and think about that song, I
get them little Y'all know what I'm
talking about. And so, praise God for
being so good. Uh, Sister Jamie, shout
out to you. The God who governs angel
armies
>> has put encampments all around me. I
love that song and I love the truth of
that song and Nicole literally
experienced it
>> firsthand. So, somebody, y'all ought to
just give God glory and praise in the
chat right now. We getting ready to go
to the throne of grace, but let's go in
to God's presence with joy and praise on
our lips. Just light that chat up right
there right now. If you know he has
delivered you. Somebody had said, "I
used to be a sailor. I had potty mouth,
too." Come on, put it in the chat. I'm
gonna put Amen. Look, I'm gonna put my
one. I got to put my one in the chat.
>> Okay, put your one in
>> cuz Lord, you brought me out and I know
you [laughter] did.
>> I can put a lot of ones in the chat.
>> Hallelujah. We'll put them in there.
Thank you, Jesus. You know, when the
Holy Ghost come, he going to give you a
new walk. He give you a new talk, give
you a new look. You think different.
Everything's different when the Holy
Ghost comes.
>> Absolutely. fill us God to overflowing.
Somebody shout hallelujah in that chat.
Well, look at here. So, saints, while
we're praising and while all the worship
is going up in the chat, God being
glorified and honored by his people.
Look at that. And we now get to
celebrate one more time because today
we're going to reintroduce you to my
beautiful sister, Sister Sharon Faith
Johnson. She came one time and the last
time she came, you know, we couldn't get
that audio on and we saw her there and
we're like, "Oh, no, no, no."
>> And she was heartbroken. So, we were
excited to bring her back.
>> This is a beautiful sister with such a
bubbly spirit. You probably remember her
testimony some time ago and here she is.
Come on, Sister Sharon.
>> You know what I just have to say about
>> Absolutely. Love is the way.
>> Can you hear me?
>> Yes, we can. Sharon, I was just saying
finally. finally how she I love how she
reads the word. She's so animated and
the way that she reads scripture, it
comes to life when she reads it. I just
love when she
>> Amen. Thank you, Sister Sharon, for
joining us today.
>> Amen. Amen. I'm just so glad to be here
and you all can hear me, right? Want to
make sure.
>> Yes, we can.
>> Praise the Lord. Praise the Lord. First
of all, just want to say uh it's an
honor just to just to meet you all. Even
though it's virtual, it's an honor to
meet you, Brother Terry and Sister
Amira.
>> Amen.
>> Okay.
>> Thank you all so much. Look, hello and
happy Sabbath to everyone across and
around the world from state to state,
country to country. Hey, happy Sabbath
to you. And we want to encourage you to
put your prayer uh in the chat, email
us, text us, however way you want to do
it. Okay, the prayer warriors are on
standby to get your prayer. And to me,
they remind me of angels, okay, taking
those requests and they're going to
submit them to the throne of grace. But
not only are they're going to submit
your requests to the throne of grace.
Guess what? They're going to submit you
to the throne of grace with your prayer.
So, praise the Lord. We have three
>> uh prayer requests and on the third one
it's a threepart. So we're going to go
ahead on with intercessory prayer. But
before we do that, we're going to go to
the throne of grace and mercy and go
give God his glory first before we start
submitting requests. Father God in
heaven, we come before thee in the name
of our Lord Jesus Christ. And we thank
you for being the great I am, being the
great God of the universe, the most
powerful God of the universe and
throughout all the galaxies. Thank you
Lord for creating us. Thank you Lord for
making us. Thank you Lord for sending
your only son Jesus Christ to make the
way for us oh Lord to be with you. He
came and manifested your character but
also to manifest your character in our
lives. And so, Father, we thank you so
much. And Lord, we want to thank you for
the Holy Spirit because he said, "If I
don't go, the comforter will not come."
So, we thank you for the comforter
because he has came to comfort our
minds, to comfort our hearts. And so,
Father, we give you that praise, that
honor, and that glory that you so richly
deserve in Jesus conquering name. Amen.
So, we got a prayer that's from
>> at MO1.05-
S9R
at EM1. We want to thank you for
submitting your prayer request, a
virtual hug from us to you. All right.
Please pray for my mom's eye surgery
this Monday to go well. And M01 says,
"Thank you." All right. Father God, we
come before thee in the name of Jesus,
oh God. And we thank you for this uh
beautiful request that has come from me.
We want to thank you, Lord, because me
knows that you are a powerful God and
that you're able to do that nobody else
can do. So, Father, we bring her mom to
your throne of grace and ask, oh God,
that when she gets ready to have this
surgery on Monday, oh God, that you will
bless all of the team of the doctors and
all of the nurses, the uh and everybody
that's involved with this surgery, oh
God, to work accordingly and be on one
accord that you will work with them and
guide them through this surgery, oh God.
And we ask that you will bless her mom
and give her uh calmness, oh God, and
give me calmness as well as she go
through this surgery. And we pray that
this surgery will be a phenomenal and a
success. Lord, we thank you and we
praise you for this in Jesus' name.
Amen. The second request is coming from
Denise Richardson 5970.
Please pray pray for my mother Irma. She
is not well at all and I've been asked
to come home. Please pray for God
provides healing for her and strengthen
me. Father uh God in heaven, we thank
you Lord for our dear sister Denise who
have submitted her prayer request oh God
for her mom. So father we ask for
healing in the name of Jesus. We know
that you are a God that can heal, touch,
save, deliver. Oh God, we know that you
will do it. And so, Father, we ask, oh
God, that you will heal her mom. But at
the same time, give Sister Denise, oh
God, peace and assurance that you are
with her as she go to see her mom. Grant
her traveling graces and mercy to get
there in the name of Jesus. Be with this
family, God, and bless them and take
care of them. take care of her mom in
the name of our Lord Jesus. And so,
Father God, we thank you in Jesus name.
Amen. We got another prayer request and
it's coming from at Student of the
Master. I love that at Student of the
Master Prayer. The first uh it's a
three-part prayer request and the first
one is pray for my family that they may
believe. Wow. We just thank you so much
for sending in this prayer request at
student of the master. Father God, we
pray oh Lord for the student of the
master. We pray for their family. Oh
God, Lord, whatever is in the way
blocking them from seeing you. We ask oh
God that you remove all those
distractions of Satan. Remove everything
out the way so they can see you, so they
can hear you, oh Lord, in the name of
Jesus. And Lord, we ask that you will
open their minds and their heart. Open
their ears, oh God, so that they can
receive you in the name of Jesus. Put
people around them that will lead them
to Christ so they can hear Christ, oh
God. And we thank you so much in Jesus'
name. Amen. Um, we got a second part. A
colleague had to have a heart monitor
because of chest pains. Father God, we
thank you, Lord. We thank you, Lord. We
know that you are able to heal. We know
that you are able to deliver this
colleague, oh God, out of the pains that
they're experiencing. And so, Father, we
bring this colleague right now to the
throne of grace. And we ask in the name
of Jesus for a healing. We ask, oh God,
that you will uh send this colleague to
the hospital so they can figure out what
is going on. These are trained
professionals that you have blessed them
with the skills to know how to monitor
to this type of situation. And so father
we ask in the name of Jesus for healing
and that he would get this colleague
would get the assistance that he needs
and we thank you in the name of Jesus.
And the third part is pray that we all
monitor our hearts through the Holy
Spirit. Amen. I love that prayer
request. Father God in heaven, we pray,
oh God, for the Holy Spirit to monitor
through all of our hearts. Oh God, the
Holy Spirit is to lead us and to guide
us through all truth and direction. He
points us and leads us to the way. Jesus
Jesus said, "I am the way. I am truth. I
am life. No man can come unto the father
but by me." And so, Father, we pray for
this monitoring of the Holy Spirit that
he rest and abide in our lives. He rest
upon us, oh God, so that we can live the
perfect life of our Lord Jesus Christ.
And so, Father, we thank you so much for
being our God, listening to our prayers,
hearing our prayers, and oh God, sending
answers from heaven and bringing good
tidings to the earth. and we thank you
so much and pray these things in Jesus
holy name. Amen.
>> Amen. Amen. Amen. And sister Sharon want
to thank you so much for stepping in and
praying for us. Want to ask that uh also
would you pray for all of the prayer
requests in the chat that we did not get
a chance to mention just unspoken ones
and ones that names that we weren't
heard. And and we want to remind you if
you're watching, we will be uh gathering
all these prayer requests and praying
for them throughout the week. But Sister
Sharon's going to pray for those and for
the message that we're about to hear
from pastor.
>> Amen. Amen. Father God, we thank you
Lord again for being our God. Lord, we
know that you see all the prayer
requests, oh God, that are being put in
the chat or maybe the prayer requests
that are in somebody's heart. Maybe the
prayer request is that and through the
tears, oh God. And Father God, we ask,
oh God, that you would step in for them,
step in for them and answer their
prayers, oh God, in the name of Jesus.
And Lord, we thank you for these prayer
requests. We thank you for these
precious souls because you said every
soul is precious in your sight. And we
thank you so much in the powerful,
wonderful name of our Lord, our Savior
Jesus Christ the King. Amen.
>> Amen.
>> Thank you, Sharon.
You were the word at the beginning,
one with God the Lord [singing] most
[music] high.
Your hidden glory [singing]
in creation
now revealed [singing]
in you [music]
are Christ. What a beautiful name
[singing] it is. [music]
What a beautiful name it is.
The name of Jesus [singing]
Christ [music] our King.
What a beautiful name [singing] it is.
[music]
Nothing can stand against.
What a beautiful [singing] name it is.
[music] The name of Jesus.
You didn't want heaven without us.
So Jesus, you brought heaven [singing]
down. Our [music]
sin was great, [singing] your love was
[music] greater.
And what can separate
us now?
What a wonderful name it is. [music]
What a wonderful name it is.
The name of Jesus
Christ our King.
What a wonderful name it is. [music]
Nothing compares to this. [singing]
What a wonderful name it is. The name of
Jesus.
[music]
Oh, the name, [singing and music]
the name,
the name [singing] of Jesus.
Oh,
[music] there's power in the name.
[music]
Death could not hold you. The veil are
before you. He silenced the boast of sin
and grave.
The heavens are roaring.
The praise [music and singing] of your
glory
for you are raised to life [singing]
again.
You have no rivals. [singing]
You have no equals
now and [singing] forever.
God, you reign.
Yours is the [singing] kingom.
Yours is the glory.
Yours is [music] the name
above [singing]
all names.
What a powerful name it is.
What a powerful [singing] name it is.
The name [music] of Jesus
Christ [singing] our King. What a
[music] powerful name it is.
Nothing can stand against.
What a powerful name it is. [music]
The name [singing]
of Jesus.
What a powerful name it is.
What a powerful [singing] name it is.
[music]
What a powerful name [singing] it is.
Nothing can stand against
what a powerful [music and singing] name
it is. The name of Jesus. [music]
>> [music]
>> Yes.
Amen. Amen. Happy Sabbath living man of
church family. Uh I want to invite you I
want to invite you to take this time to
share this link and invite everyone that
you can because I need people we need
people to hear this message today. And
this is going to be an in-house message,
you guys. Um, we're going to have to
we're going to talk about some in-house
things that I think are very important
for God's people, especially in the time
that we're living in.
Um, the title of the message today is
this man eateth with sinners. This man
eateth with sinners. I want to invite
you to pray with me. Heavenly Father,
we're asking Lord today that in a
special way you would please speak to
your people. Lord, hide me behind your
cross.
Lord, infuse me with your spirit. And
Lord, may the words I speak
be uplifting and glorifying to you. We
pray in Jesus name. Amen.
So guys, um I want to address something
uh that occurred over the last over last
Sabbath
that has now um
kind of gone
very public, let me say, uh within our
church.
So, a few months back, um I was invited
to actually speak at a religious liberty
event for um the 7th Day Adventist
Church in Han, uh the Hansen 7th Day
Adventist Church in Brooklyn, New York.
And I was told that there were going to
be several politicians there and that
these politicians were supposed to only
speak on religious liberty. So, they
were being invited, but we weren't sure
if they weren't sure if they were going
to come. And uh to me, I was like, "Hey,
listen. If I if I'm able to be there and
to preach
a message on religious liberty and the
separation of church and state in the
presence of um politicians and I was
told there were going to be politicians
from the left, politicians from the
right. Uh and um I was like, Lord, what
an opportunity. What an opportunity. I
was told they were not going to be
politicking. And um and so anyway, we
accepted the invitation.
And uh when we got to New York last
weekend uh Friday and we were uh
fellowshipping with uh some of the uh
with actually one of the one of the uh
organizers of the of the event and I
remember we were there eating lunch uh
Friday afternoon and he was on a phone
with several of the the politicians
um uh offices and they were like taking
notes like okay so remember no uh
political talk. Um and then I I even
heard him over say, "Make sure that they
greet the speaker, the pastor that's
going to be speaking." And in my head,
I'm I'm kind of like, "They don't even
know me." Like, but hey, it's a
formality, so let it be. And so,
uh I'm looking forward to, you know,
hopefully meeting all of these
politicians because, man, what an
opportunity.
What an opportunity
to be able to share with them. Even if I
don't get to do it that there, I don't I
mean, I didn't know how long they were
going to be sticking around or what. I
had no clue, but even if I got to meet
some of them that the Lord would would
would be able to plant seeds later down
the road, I thought, man, what a great
opportunity. So, Sabbath morning comes
around
and um the only one that actually came
early and actually walked into the back
room while my wife and I were there uh
into the pastor's office was um Zoron
Manni.
Zoran Mdani.
I I didn't know what the guy looked
like. I never heard his name before.
I didn't know he was running for mayor.
because I don't follow New York
politics.
Like I think I may have asked my wife,
"Who's that again?" And she's like, "The
guy that's running for mayor." This is
like, you know, 20 30 minutes before he
comes into the office.
The name I heard was Hakee Jeff that was
going to be there. And that was that was
the name that I knew. And I was like, I
wonder if I'm going to get to meet him.
So when Zoron comes in and you know just
a little little bit earlier, my wife was
like, "That's the guy that's running for
mayor for New York." And I'm like,
"Okay, so okay, this is a guy running
for mayor for New York." I didn't know
he was as well known as he was. I didn't
know that.
And so he comes in and we greet and uh
we greet each other. Um and he, you
know, he's very just, you know, warm
personality. Um, and
someone took a picture of us and our our
exchange was probably like maybe a
minute. So then we all have to go out
and it's only him. He's the only one
there. Some of the other politicians
don't come till later. And I remember as
I was sitting sitting down in the pew
and I was sitting next to one of the
organizers and he was just like he was
saying to me,"Lord, please do not do not
let them, you know, go off course. We
have done everything we could to let
them know please stay on religious
liberty."
And I said to him, "Yeah, you know how
those YouTube channels go. Uh they just
looking for something.
So Zoron gets up and he's speaking and
uh he he uh says, "I want to thank I
don't even know what he said. I think he
said Evore me." What?
He butchered my name. And I was like,
"Well, no one's going to even recognize
that." And I just kind of chuckled in my
mind like, "Yeah, cuz he doesn't know
me." Evil Eevee. Eevee M, whatever he
said.
And so, uh, um, you know, they say what
they say and some of them, you know,
veer off a little bit and I'm just like,
but I know that the that that the
leaders instructed them, do not speak on
anything political. This is about
religious liberty. And they all agreed.
So, I get up and I do my sermon. It's on
Revelation chapter 13. It's on the third
angel's message. It's on the close of
probation. It's on the the uh um uh uh
apostate Protestantism. It is our
message.
We leave the following day. And that
morning, my wife happened to post the
picture. I didn't even know she was
posting it. Posted the picture
um on her Instagram. I had no idea that
she that she had done that. And in the
picture, she tagged me, Ivormeyers. And
then she thought she was tagging uh uh
Zoron in a way that to say, "Hey, you
know, this is a way that, you know,
trying to stay connected with him so
that he could see, hey, we posted this,
you know, we posted the picture."
Um, and
the post that she chose when all the I
mean, the tag that she chose when all
the tags came up was uh Zoron for mayor.
So, it looked like she was endorsing
Zoron for mayor. Now, I didn't know this
till after the plane landed in
Huntsville, Alabama. And um somebody
calls me and says, "Pastor, uh there are
people saying that you endorsed uh the
guy running for mayor." And I was like,
"Why would I endorse somebody that I
don't know that I just met that I don't
know about his politics? Like, I just
met him. That doesn't make sense." And
they were like, "Well, on your wife's
Instagram there's a picture." And I'm
like, "But that that's just a picture."
And they were like, "Well, it says Zoron
fam mayor." And I was like, "What?"
So, I opened my phone, looked at the
picture, and I was like, "This
is saying that you're, you know, we're
endorsing
uh this guy for mayor." And she was
like, "No, I'm tagging him." And I was
like, "Well,
we got to tag him with something else
because we're not endorsing him." And
she was like, "Okay." And it looks like
this is his wrong tag anyway. So, she
took the picture down, put it back up.
By the way, they had already told me
this picture has already been shared and
people are saying you're endorsing a
candidate. If I had been endorsing a
candidate, the picture would still be up
with the hashtag.
So, all of this to say you guys that um
that later that even I actually put up a
post and said, "Hey guys, no, this is
not what happened." And that was it you
guys. and I became a Muslim
uh supporter.
What are you doing standing with this
man? He's a Democrat. He's evil. He's
wicked. And in essence,
the sentiment was this man taketh
pictures with sinners. There is a basis
of the message, you guys. There's a
basis of the message. I remember a few
uh within the last month a lot of my
Adventist brothers and sisters were
talking about the importance of context
and how you can't take a sentence from
someone online out of context and you
know you got to look at the context and
and even though things you know may seem
X Y and Z you got to look at the context
and so surely I was like well you know
they're going to they're going to
consider context they're going to know
that but no no the the same people that
were talking about context text context
suddenly didn't matter.
This is the foundation, guys. I'm I'm
setting the foundation, the stage
because videos were made and and none of
the people ever stopped to say, "Hey,
let's go and talk to Pastor Myers and
see, hey, what was the situation behind
this? Like, what happened?" It's all
right to be confused and say, "Hey, that
you know what was going on." But before
we jump to conclusions and start putting
out posts and videos and things of that
nature, I want to speak to something
that I believe is happening in our
church that
that has the devil smiling.
I want to go to the screen and I want to
read a statement from uh the spirit of
prophecy. And the sermon has now begun.
Ellen White says these words. She
says,"I saw
that the very spirit of perjury that
would turn truth into falsehood, good
into evil, and innocence into crime is
now active.
Satan exalts over the condition of God's
professed people.
While many are neglecting their own
souls, they eagerly watch for an
opportunity to criticize
and condemn
others.
All have defects of character, and it is
not hard to find something that jealousy
can interpret to their injury. Now, say
these self-constituted judges, we have
the facts. We will fasten upon them an
accusation from which they cannot clear
themselves. We got the picture, y'all.
We have the picture and we have the
hashtag. It is the smoking gun.
They wait for a fitting opportunity and
then produce their bundle of gossip and
bring forth their tidbits.
Let me talk about this definition of
perjury for a moment because she says
here, I saw the spirit of perjury. Let
me read it again. I saw that the very
spirit of perjury that would turn truth
into falsehood, good into evil, and
innocence into crime is now active and
so among God's people. So, what is
perjury?
Perjury is the offense of willfully
telling an untruth in a court after
having taken an oath or affirmation.
That's what perjury is. I want to read
on and I want you to notice this. Uh the
prefix purr in Latin [clears throat]
often meant harmful.
So witnesses who perger themselves do
harm to the truth by knowingly telling a
lie. Not all lying is perjury. Only
lying under an oath. So perjury perjury
generally takes place either in court or
before a legislative body such as
Congress. To avoid committing perjury, a
witness or defendant may simply take the
fifth, that is refuse to answer a
question because the answer might be an
admission of guilt. And the fifth
amendment to the constitution forbids
forcing a citizen to admit to being
guilty of a crime. Did you know
that for Christians,
taking the fifth when it comes to gossip
and spreading rumors is always the
safest thing to do. Why? Because Ellen
White just told us that the spirit of
perjury, she saw it running rampant in
the church. Now, you might say, "Well,
no, we're not in in a in a court of law.
We're not in Congress. Uh uh we're not
before a legislative body. So, and and
we're not take we haven't taken an oath.
But I want you to notice, beloved, that
Ellen White also says, "He who accepts
God as his sovereign must take the oath
of allegiance to him.
He must put on the Christian uniform and
bear a loft the banner that shows to
whose army he belongs. He must make an
open vowel of his allegiance to Christ.
Concealment is impossible. Christ's
impress Christ impress must appear on
the life in sanctified works. In other
words,
when you and I became Christians, we
took an oath. You are under an oath. And
beloved, part of that oath is to reflect
and represent the character of Christ.
Part of that oath is found in Exodus
20:16, which says, "Thou shalt not bear
false witness against thy neighbor."
When you bear false witness against your
neighbor, when you have that spirit of
perjury,
you are breaking an oath. Y'all put a
one in the chat if you understand what
I'm saying.
As Christians, as Seventh Day
Adventists, we are under an oath
to tell the truth.
And when we willingly
either omit
the truth or twist the truth
to do harm to another person's
character,
you are breaking the oath. You are under
the spirit of perjury. Listen to what
she says. In their efforts to carry a
point, persons who have naturally a
strong imagination are in danger of
deceiving themselves and deceiving
others. They gather up unguarded
expressions from another, not
considering that words may be uttered
hastily and hence may not reflect the
real sentiments
of the speaker.
But those unpremeditated remarks, often
so trifling as to be unworthy of notice,
are viewed through Satan's magnifying
glass, pondered and repeated until
molehills
become mountains.
I am so glad that God has given us the
gift of the spirit of prophecy
to reveal the spirit of truth versus the
spirit of error.
There is something going on in our
church, beloved, that is very dangerous.
It is a spirit of perjury. It is a
spirit that says, "What dirt can I find
on the next individual to make myself
look good?
That is an antichrist
spirit. Let me keep reading. Is it
Christian charity to gather up every
floating report to unearth everything
that will cast suspicion on the
character of another and then take
delight in using it to injure him? Satan
exalts when he can defame or wound a
follower of Christ. He is the accuser of
the brethren. Shall Christians aid him
in his work? Let me keep reading. The
spirit of gossip and tailbearing is one
of Satan's special agencies to sow
discord and strife, to separate friends,
and to undermine the faith of many in
the truthfulness of our positions.
Brethren and sisters are too ready to
talk of the faults of and errors they
think exist in others and especially in
those whom have borne unflinchingly the
message of reproof and warning given
them of God.
The children of these complainers listen
to me. When children see this stuff
going on y'all listen to what she says.
The children of these complainers listen
with open ears and receive the poison of
dissatisfaction.
Parents are thus blinded, caught closing
the avenues through which the hearts of
the children might be reached. How many
families season their daily meals with
doubt and questioning? They dissect the
characters of their friends and serve
them up as dainty desserts. A precious
bit of slander is passed around the
board to be commented upon not only by
adults but by children. In this, God is
dishonored. Jesus said, "In as much as
you have done it unto the least of
these, my brethren, you have done it
unto me." Matthew 25:40. Therefore,
Christ is slighted and abused by those
who slander his servants. And listen to
this next sentence. The names of God's
chosen servants have been handled with
disrespect and in some cases with
absolute contempt by persons whose duty
it is to hold them up. You know, I
remember in the Bible the story of David
and Saul. David and Saul. And and David
had such a respect for God's anointed
that even in that anointed man's
absolute corruptness,
David said, "Do not touch the Lord's
anointed."
David had that kind of reverence. And
I'll tell you
that kind of thing is gone in our
church. The the level of of respect due
to one another, it's not that the pastor
is higher than this person. The level of
respect due to one another is
disappearing
within our church.
It's happening.
So,
um um I'm going to address something
else very quickly and then I'm I'm this
is setting the foundation for what you
are about to see and you're all about to
understand something that that is
absolutely crucial you guys because one
of the [snorts] complaints that I
typically get and I even got over this
sermon was all you do is talk about
Christian nationalism
and Revelation chapter 13 and you're not
talking about this and this and this and
this and therefore you are unbalanced.
Therefore, you are unbalanced, pastor.
You're biased.
You lean this way.
You're not fair.
You don't talk about X, Y, and Z, but
you're always talking about A, B, and C.
So guys, we're about to go through a
lesson that I hope you will never
forget. This is from the Bible.
Please, I need y'all to focus. Let's
follow let's let let's move along. 2
Peter chapter 1 21 the Bible says, "For
the prophecy came not in old time by the
will of man, but holy men of God spake
as they were moved by the Holy Ghost."
So here's what I want you to understand
you guys. The Holy Ghost moved the men
of the Bible,
the prophets, the authors, the writers
to speak and write what they wrote.
Meaning the entire Bible,
the entire Bible
was inspired by the Holy Spirit. Now,
why is that important? John 16:7 says
this, "Nevertheless, I tell you the
truth. It is expedient for you that I go
away. For if I go not away, the
comforter will not come unto you. But if
I depart, I will send him unto you. and
when he has come, he will reprove the
world of sin and of righteousness and of
judgment. In other words, the work of
the Holy Spirit was to reprove. That was
one of the jobs of the Holy Spirit, to
reprove, to rebuke. Therefore, it might
be a good idea for us to go back through
the Bible and see how
the Holy Spirit rebuked. In what way can
we find a pattern of rebuke
according to how the spirit did it? And
so here's what we're going to do. We're
going to go through the whole Bible and
we're going to we're going to trace this
pattern and you're going to see
something absolutely mindblowing unfold.
Now, how many of you want to be in
unison with the Holy Spirit? Just put a
one in the chat if you want to be in
unison with the Holy Spirit. Here's what
we're going to do, you guys. We're going
to see, can we find a pattern, a ratio
of the Holy Spirit? Let's Let's see.
If we were to trace the entire Old
Testament, and by the way, here's what I
did. I went to to chat GPT and I said,
"Chat, I have a question.
I want you to take all the warnings of
the Old Testament and tell me how many
of those warnings inspired by the Holy
Spirit, how many of those warnings were
directed to unbelievers
and how many of those warnings were
directed to God's own people? And here's
what Chat GPT said. Chat GBT put out a
number for me and said approximately 70
to 85%
of the Holy Spirit's focus on reproving
in the Old Testament was towards
those professing to believe in God.
Y'all put a one in the chat. Put a one
in the chat if you could see that
clearly.
Most of the books of the Old Testament
are directed at the people of God.
That would make sense.
The Old Testament was written for
the people of God.
All right. So, so what about the New
Testament? Interestingly enough, in the
New Testament, if we were just to look
at Jesus, the Holy Spirit working
through Jesus, I want you to know what
Matthew chapter 10:5 says. Then these 12
sent forth and commanded Then these 12
Jesus sent forth and commanded them,
saying, "Go not into the way of the
Gentiles, and into any city of the
Samaritans, and to you not. But go ye
rather to the lost sheep of the house of
Israel." Interestingly enough, Jesus
says, "I've only been sent unto the lost
sheep of the house of Israel."
So, I asked Chad GBT, "Hey Chat,
how much rebuking did Jesus do to
unbelievers
versus
to the people who claimed to serve God?"
Chat GBT's response. Roughly 80 to 90%
of Jesus's rebukes
were toward people professing
to serve God.
There is barely no rebuke
to a Roman, to the Roman soldiers,
to the unbelievers, to the ungodly. Now,
we might stop and ask a question. I
might stop and ask a question. Hey, hey,
would you all say that Jesus was being
balanced? Put a five in the chat if you
think Jesus was being balanced. Put a
eight in the chat if you think Jesus was
being unbalanced because Jesus, it seems
that you are not calling out the sins of
the Romans enough. You are only focused,
Jesus,
on what those who profess to serve God
are doing. Jesus, you're not being very
balanced.
Your preaching, Jesus, seems to only
focus on those who profess to serve God.
Why aren't you talking more about the
Romans?
unbeliever? I fear that some of us, the
way we have gotten in our thinking
today, would accuse Jesus of being
biased in his preaching.
All right, how about this? Let's go to
the epistles. And I'm going to show you
something, you guys. I want you to check
this out. I want to look at every
epistle. And we're going to run through
this very quickly. I just want to show
you how they all begin. So 1 Corinthians
chapter 1:2, to all that be in Rome, I'm
sorry, Romans chapter 1:7. To all that
be in Rome, beloved of God, called to be
saints. Wow. Did you know the book of
Romans was not written to unbelievers?
Did you know the book of Romans and
everything in it was directed to the
saints in Rome?
How about 1 Corinthians 1? 1 Corinthians
1:2. Unto the church of God which is at
Corinth. 2 Corinthians 1:2. Unto the
church of God which is at Corenth.
Galatians chapter 1:2. And all the
brethren which are with me unto the
churches of Galatia. Ephesians to the
saints which are at Ephesus.
Philippians to all the saints in Christ
which are at Philippi. Colossians to the
saints and faithful brethren in Christ
which are at Coloss Colasse
Thessalonians unto the church of
Thessalonians Thessalonians unto the
church of Thessalonians. That's 1 and 2
Thessalonians. Timothy Paul unto Timothy
my own son in the faith. Second Timothy
Paul to Timothy my beloved son in the
faith. Titus to Titus my own son after
the common faith. Fleiman Paul a
prisoner of Jesus Christ and Timothy our
brother. unto Fleiman our dearly beloved
and fellow laborer and to our beloved
Afia and Archipus our fellow soldier and
to the church in thy house. Hebrews God
who at sunundry times and in diverse
manner spake in time past unto the
fathers by the prophets has in these
last days spoken unto us by his son.
We're almost there you guys. James
chapter 1, James to the 12 tribes which
are scattered abroad. Heb first Peter
chapter 1 to the strangers scattered
through Pontius and Galatia, Capidosia,
Asia, Bithnneia, elect according to the
fornowledge of God the Father. Uh second
Peter, Simon Peter, to them that have
obtained like precious faith. First
John, that which we have seen and held,
declare we unto you that we may have
that you may have fellowship with us.
And truly our fellowship is with the
father and with the son Jesus Christ. 2
John 1 to the elder and the elect lady
and her children whom I love in the
truth. Third John to the elder and to
unto the well-beloved Gaes. Jude Jude to
them that are sanctified. Revelation to
the seven churches which are in Asia. Do
y'all see what just happened? Every
epistle, you guys, these epistles,
listen carefully to me, they were not
written to unbelievers.
So all the counsel, all the rebuke in
these books
are towards
believers.
The entire Bible
written towards believers, rebuke
towards believers. And in fact, the
rebuke when when it dealt with the the
Gentiles or the Romans or the
unbeliever, the rebuke was don't be like
them.
So I asked Chad GBT, what is the
percentage of internal rebuke versus
rebuke for the unbeliever? And again,
wow, look at that. 85 to 95% from Acts
all the way to Revelation is focused on
rebuke of professed believers. And I got
to ask you a question. For those of you
who say, "Oh, you know, your preaching
is is unbalanced. You you only do this
percent of this, but you do a whole
bunch of that." Would you say that the
Bible and Jesus and the prophets were
unbalanced?
[clears throat]
So,
let's just break down the book of
Revelation. I asked chat GPT the same
question and
it says 80 to 90%
of the book of revelation is focused
on the believers.
There is a chapter Revelation 11 that
speaks to atheism. Revelation chapter 9
and 10 or 8 and 9 that speaks to the
rise of Islam. But by far, the majority
of the book is exposing a counterfeit
Christian power.
Let's talk let's talk for a moment about
the spirit of prophecy.
So, we've looked at the Bible and we've
seen that there is this ratio that keeps
popping up 80 to 90%
Rebuke
is given to those who profess Christ and
very little to those to the unbelievers.
And so I said, hm, what about the
testimonies? By the way, this is so
interesting, you guys. So, so when I put
in the testimonies, here's what chat
chatbt said. 70 to 85% is internal
rebuke. Now it's interesting that the
testimonies are called the testimonies
to the churches.
That's what it's called the testimony.
The testimonies to the churches. In
other words, the testimonies are not for
the unbeliever.
But you know what happens you guys? You
know what happens? What book? Let me ask
you, what book
would you give to an atheist that was
written by Ellen White? What book would
you give to an unbeliever?
Someone who is not a an a Christian
that believes in the Bible already, but
is doesn't believe in anything else,
doesn't believe in the B, doesn't know
Jesus. What book would you give of Ellen
White's?
Come on, y'all. Y'all y'all know, right?
Are y'all putting it in the chat?
You're either saying Desire of Ages or
Steps to Christ. Wow.
How much rebuke do you think is in steps
to Christ
for the unbeliever? The person that's
trying to make their way to Jesus, the
person that doesn't know Christ.
Isn't that interesting?
It seems like the writings of the spirit
of prophecy actually follow along the
same ratio of the Holy Spirit that we
see in the Bible. In fact, in fact, if
if we uh uh take the book the great
controversy and ask the same question,
how much of the book The Great
Controversy, which would be a book that
I would give, let's say, to someone who
believes in Jesus but has prophecy all
wrong.
That's the book that I would give to
them. I wouldn't give them steps to
Christ because they have already
accepted Christ. They they already said,
"Hey, I believe in Christ." So, I would
give I would give the person who claims
to believe in Jesus the great
controversy. How much rebuke do you
think is in the great controversy for
the unbeliever versus for a professed
Christian power? That's right, you guys.
75 to 90%
of the book
and it says there is one chapter that
deals with the French Revolution.
There's one other chapter that deals
with Rome as it was persecuting the
early Christians.
BUT THE MAJORITY OF THE BOOK, and I
would ask a question, is Ellen White
being unbalanced in her approach?
Because now the big the the the the
battlecry seems to be the word balance.
Balance.
But beloved, we see what balance is in
the divine realm. We see what balance is
according to the Bible. The discip the
the Pharisees did not like Jesus because
they thought he was unbalanced.
They thought Jesus was unbalanced.
Y'all,
do you know what Ellen White says is the
cause of so much ungodliness in the
world? Let me read it to you. The light
esteemed the light esteem in which the
law of God is held even by religious
leaders has been productive of great
evil. The teaching which has become so
widespread that the device that the
divine statutes are no longer abiding
upon men is is the same as idolatry in
its effect upon the morals of the
people. Those who seek to lessen the
claims of God's holy law are striking
directly at the foundation of the
government of families and nations.
Religious parents fa failing to walk in
his statutes do not command their
households to keep the way of the Lord.
The law of God is not made the rule of
life. The children as they make homes of
their own feel under no obligation to
teach their children what they
themselves have never been taught. And
this is why there are so many godless
families. This is why depravity is so
deep and widespread. In other words, the
spirit of prophecy
which is the Holy Spirit
writing through write the Holy Spirit
moving Ellen White to speak says the
blame for the ungodliness of our society
lays at the feet of religious teachers
who claim that the law of God has been
done away with.
So then in our experiment we see after
when we recap we see wow look at that
there's this constant line of between 70
to 90% of the rebuke by the Holy Spirit
is always towards those professing to be
believers in God while only a small if
y'all ask me pastor why do you not focus
more on the ungodly unbeliever believers
and the people who are who are rejecting
God altogether. If you ask me why,
beloved, I will simply tell you I am
following the leadings of the Holy
Spirit. That's why I'm focusing on what
Jesus f focused on. I'm focusing on what
Ellen White focused on. I'm focusing on
what the entire Bible I'm following that
pattern. I'm following that ratio. That
is what balance is.
Balance is not what we think. Balance is
what God thinks.
Now the question you might ask is why
does the Holy Spirit follow this
pattern?
Why is the Holy Spirit pointing its
rebuke to those who profess to be
followers of God? And the answer is
found right here in Isaiah 60:1. The
Bible says, "Arise, shine, for thy light
is come and the glory of the Lord is
risen upon thee. For behold, the
darkness shall cover the earth, and
gross darkness the people. But the Lord
shall arise upon thee, and his glory
shall be seen upon thee, and the
Gentiles shall come to thy light, and
kings to the brightness of thy rising.
Lift up thine eyes round about see. All
they gather themselves together. They
come to thee. Thy son shall come from
afar, and thy daughters shall be nursed
at thy side. Then thou shalt see and
flow together, and thine heart shall
fear and be enlarged, because the
abundance of the sea shall be converted
unto thee. The forces of the Gentiles
shall come unto thee. In other words,
beloved, what God is saying is that the
reason, listen to me y'all, the reason
why my emphasis is on those who profess
to know me is because they are the very
light I am trying to use to bring
non-believers and atheists and Gentiles
and Marxists and socialists and Muslims
and Buddhists and everybody else who
does not call the name of Jesus. I need
you believers to actually be light. And
when you are light, that's what's going
to draw them. But you are being
darkness. And darkness is is what is
securing them in what they believe.
Because when they look at you, all they
see is hate and animosity and darkness.
And y'all are not like us.
That's why God turns his rebuke
on the church.
And when I say the church, do not get
don't do not misstate what I'm saying.
When I say the church, I'm talking about
anyone anywhere in the world, in any
denomination that claims to be a
follower of Jesus. Because the thing
that Jesus is most concerned about is
false representation. I have called you
to be a light in this world. And when
you begin to go out and tell people that
the Sabbath has been changed, that the
law of God has been done away with, that
when the dead die, they go straight to
heaven, you are not miss, you are not
representing the truth.
And so for those of us who know the
truth,
our major focus should be on any false
representation of what Jesus represents.
Our focus, beloved, is not on condemning
the gentile, the Muslim. PASTOR, WHAT
ARE YOU DOING standing next to a Muslim?
How dare
you
disrespect
the character of Jesus by saying, "How
dare a believer be seen in the presence
of an unbeliever?"
That is straight up Phariseism.
And in the name of God, I rebuke you,
whoever you are.
In the name of God, you will answer
to the Lord God Almighty
for having the same spirit of the
Pharisees who thought that they were too
good and holy to be found in the
presence of a gentile of an unbeliever.
Romans 2:22 says, "Thou says a man
should not commit adultery adultery.
Dust thou commit adultery? Thou that
aboreest idols, dust thou commit
sacrilege? Thou that makest thy boast of
the law, through breaking the law,
dishonest thou God? For the name of God
is blasphemed among the Gentiles through
you, as it is written.
Your
wicked
idea of what righteousness is
is what leads unbelievers to blaspheme
the God of heaven.
And everyone that possesses that spirit
ought to be rebuked
because that is not the spirit of our
savior. This man
eateth with sinners.
This man taketh a picture with sinners.
Explain yourself, pastor.
What meanth this picture?
The Bible says in 2 Timothy 3:16, "All
scripture is given by God by inspiration
of God, and is profitable for doctrine,
for reproof, for correction, for
instruction, and righteousness, that the
man of God, not the unbeliever,
the man of God may be perfect,
thoroughly furnished unto all good
works." So beloved, if the scripture is
for the man of God to be perfect, then
our role as believers is to help those
who are not men of God become men of God
so that the scripture that can then do
its work on him.
The Bible
is written
to the believer.
It is for the world,
but the instructions are for the
believer. And those instructions say,
"You are the light of the world." Now,
now that you got that right, now that
you're representing me, right, go out
and witness. But what's happening is
many of us are taking a false witness of
Jesus to the world.
And we become so invol so caught up in
the false witness that it becomes easy
for us to false witness elsewhere.
There is a divinely inspired ratio. And
I'm not saying these numbers are set
solid. I'm simply saying God spent more,
the Holy Spirit spent more of its rebuke
on those professing to believe in God
than it did on the unbeliever.
But the Pharisees wanted to flip that
ratio. They didn't like that ratio. Why
you not talking about the Romans, Jesus?
Why are you always pointing out our
sins?
You must be down with the Romans.
You must be a secret Roman. You must be
down with the opposition. You must be
down with be elabub
because your messages, Jesus, are so
unbalanced.
You harp on us all the time. Yeah, I
used to listen to Jesus, but once I
really started listening to him, he's
just unbalanced, man. All he talks
about,
all he talks about, he never talks about
the Romans.
The Jews cultivated a spirit of
retaliation. In their hatred of the
Romans, they gave utterance to hard
denunciations and pleased the wicked one
by manifesting his attributes. Thus,
they were training themselves to do the
terrible deeds which he led them on. In
the religious life of the Pharisees,
there was nothing to recommend piety to
the Gentiles. Jesus bade them not to
deceive themselves with the thought that
they could in heart rise up against
their oppressors and cherish the longing
to avenge their wrongs. Pastor, what are
you doing with a Muslim?
That is the very spirit of Antichrist.
That is the very spirit of Satan.
That is a satanic
mentality.
Are you a Muslim now? Are you a
socialist? Or are you this? Are you
that?
Perjury. The spirit of perjury. And we
don't care. Do y'all do we understand
that for every false statement that you
make whether in secret or in public, do
you know do we not understand that you
are going to have to stand before God
and explain why you said this of
someone's character? Why you said that
that this person really deep down thinks
this or says that? And even though he
says, "No, I didn't know THE GUY
BEFORE." YOU'RE LIKE, "NO, he's lying
and and I have evidence to prove it." Do
you realize you guys that the spirit of
perjury will get you lost?
Do we not believe in an investigative
judgment? Do we think that's a joke? Do
you So listen y'all. Perjury is willing
to lie under oath. Which means some of
us are so deceived by the devil that we
would be willing to risk our salvation
to accuse another brother or sister
and think that we can read their hearts.
Do we believe in in an investigative
judgment or not?
Because how can you be willing to risk
your salvation by trying to read
somebody else's mind and say, "Well,
this is what they really think and what
they really feel."
I got the dirt on them.
And even though they're saying, "Nah,
no, no." So, listen y'all, if someone
accuses you of being an Adventist, I'll
defend that all day long. If someone
accuses me of of uh uh you know being
believing in in uh um uh the Sabbath,
I'll defend that all day. If you accuse
me of believing in Sunday worship, how
can I defend something that's not my
position? How can I do that?
And when we put things upon people,
you guys, it is a spirit of perjury.
And so many of us in the church don't
even realize
that we are working our way to
destruction,
thinking [snorts] that we're doing
something righteous.
Let me show you. Come on. We're not
done. We got more to go. your gods. You
guys listen.
Were there commands and traditions to be
treated with indifference? In fact, let
me go back. Let me go back. Yeah, here
it is.
The least difference of opinion
expressed by Christ was an occasion for
the Jews to resist and denounce him.
Wow. Does that sound like present day
a lot of present day people within
Adventism?
The least difference of opinion
expressed by Christ was an occasion for
the Jews to resist and denounce him.
At times they charge him with working
miracles through Beelub, the prince of
devils. The least mention of Christ as a
light to the Gentiles, roused to fury
the NATIONAL PREJUDICE. THAT GUY'S A
MUSLIM. I MEAN A GENTILE. DON'T you know
Jesus?
Don't you know what he's really trying
to do? The worst passions of the heart
were stirred. For the Pharisees had
taught the Jewish people to despise and
hate the Muslims. I'm sorry, the
Gentiles,
the unbeliever, the atheist,
the person that rejects God, the person
that doesn't think God exists. They were
taught to hate them.
Were their commands and traditions to be
treated with indifference and worse
still to be brushed away as error? Was
this man the son of a carpenter to be
accepted as knowing more than the
priests and rulers? They would show him
that he could not take the people from
them. They determined to put him to
death. And you know what they started
doing? She says spies were constantly
upon his track seeking to catch him in
his words that they might find
accusation against him. I'm I'm going to
tell y'all a personal experience.
I got I got caught among sinners once
and it changed so much in my ministry
because people were like, "We caught you
hanging out with sinners."
I remember when the when the Black Lives
Matter thing was happening and I was
saying to myself, you know what, man,
Black Lives Matter, I I they're trying
to do right, but they don't have the
answer. They as an organization, they're
not the answer. Like what they're doing
is not the answer. The answer is only in
the gospel. And you know what? What a
perfect opportunity for us to show that
listen, Black Lives Matter, uh um uh the
NAACP, like they don't I mean, they're
doing what they think is right, but they
don't have the real answer. We have the
answer. The answer to bringing unity
between black and white, to bringing
unity between all races, to let people
know one race, many colors, one race,
many colors. The answer is the gospel.
So, you know what we're going to do?
Here's what we're going to do.
We're going to hold a peaceful protest.
We're going to let people know, hey, we
know that there's an issue. We We get
it. We understand. We're with you. We
know there's an issue. But here's what
we're going to do. We're going to take
we're going to we're going to lead a
peaceful demonstration. Then we're going
to march these people back to our
church. And then I'm going to preach to
them the everlasting gospel. And we led
about 400
people back to the front of our church.
a peaceful march and then they sat and
listened to me preach the gospel and
because the churches were closed because
it was co people were like when your
church opens up I want to come
nah
that's when I crossed the line you guys
I was caught
with Gentiles
I became a black lives matter a
supporter, which I never was. I became a
Marxist, which I'm not. I became all I
became a racist.
I became so many things. And as I read
the statement, spies were constantly
upon his track, seeking to catch him in
his words that they might find
accusation against him. I can kind of
relate with that.
How can we be treating one another in
the church like this? How can we be
actually in a m in a mindset of trying
to destroy those that we disagree with?
Floating rumors, listen, floating rumors
are often the destroyers of unity among
brethren. There are some who watch with
open mind and ears to catch flying
scandal. They gather up little incidents
which may be trifling in themselves but
which are repeated and exaggerated until
a man is made an offender for a word.
Their model seems to be report and we
will report it. These tailbears, these
YouTube channels,
these Facebook posts
are doing the work are doing Satan's
work with surprising fidelity, little
knowing how offensive their course is to
God.
If they would spend half the energy and
zeal that is given to this unholy work
in examining their own hearts, they
would find so much to do to cleanse
their souls from impurity that they
would have no time or disposition to
criticize their brethren and they would
not fall under the power of this
temptation. The door of the mind should
be closed against they say or I have
heard. We should not, why should we not,
instead of allowing jealousy or evil
surmising to come into our hearts, go to
our brethren. I saw a sermon you
preached the other day, my brother, and
I want to come to you and speak to you
and ask you, do you really believe?
Is this what you were say? Because maybe
I don't know. And instead of me jumping
to conclusions and saying, look at what
pastor so and so preached. No, you know
what? Let me go. Yes, it's public, but
because that's my brother and I love
him, let me go to my brother in private.
But you know what? It is a spirit of
hatred. Y'all listen to me carefully. It
is the spirit because I guarantee you,
every person that does this, if it were
their own mother, brother, father,
whatever, their own family member, they
would go to them in private and be like,
"Hey, is this what you really believe?
Well, man, maybe you should, you know,
because people are going to say blah
blah blah blah blah. It is the lack of
love.
Period.
It is the lack of love dwelling in the
human heart that allows people to do
what they do when they do this unholy
work.
Why should we not instead of allowing
evil, jealousy or evil surmising come
into our hearts, go to our brethren and
after frankly but kindly setting before
them the things which we have heard
detrimental to their character and
influence pray with them and for them.
Nah, nah nah, that's not good enough.
While we cannot fellowship with those
who are the bitterest enemies of Christ,
we should cultivate that spirit of
meekness and love that characterize our
master. a love that thinkketh no evil
and is not easily provoked.
So, so the Pharisees were unhappy with
Jesus. They didn't like the balance. So,
they wanted to try to find a way to
begin to accuse him. And here's what
they began doing. You guys, I want you
to notice on the screen Luke 7:38.
Listen what the Bible says. So this
woman uh uh stood at his feet weeping
and began to wash his feet with her hair
with her with her tears and did wipe
them with her hair hairs of her head and
kissed her feet kissed his feet and
anointed them with the ointment and
anointed them with ointment. Now when
the Pharisees which had bidden him saw
it, he spake within himself, saying,
"This man, if he were a prophet, would
have known what manner of woman that is
touching him. for she is a sinner. You
get that? She's a sinner. Not me. I'm
not a sinner. And Jesus, if you knew
better, you would not have been caught
having this woman in your presence.
That was a spirit of Satan. That was a
spirit of the Pharisees. In Luke 15:1,
then drew near unto him all the
publicans and sinners for to hear him.
And the Pharisees and scribes murmured,
saying, "This man receiveth sinners and
eateth with them."
That was their complaint.
Jesus, explain this picture.
Explain this image. No, no, no, no, no,
no. You owe us an explanation. Instead
of seeing, wow, Jesus is connecting with
them. What they chose to see was based
on the evil intents
in their own hearts. Explain it.
Come on. I'm all ears. Why
are you
with these publicans and sinners?
Luke 5:30. But the scribes and Pharisees
murmured against his his disciples,
saying, "Why do you eat and drink with
publicans and sinners? Don't you know
who that guy is?" Listen y'all.
Eating with publicans and sinners is one
thing, but that's a Muslim.
The spirit of Satan is running rampant
in our church,
in the hearts of people within our
church. Why? Because people in our
church have learned to hate. And I
wonder where we got that from. We must
be watching that occur someplace else.
Because this spirit of hatred within
Christians is it's it's unfathomable.
Where are we getting the spirit from?
And then we hide it under a disguise of
righteousness. We're just being
righteous protectors of the truth. No,
you're being satanic.
That's what that is. Where where are we
learning this from?
Are we are we looking at other churches
and picking up their spirit?
Because it sure seems, beloved, like
that's what's happening. Proverbs 11:1
says, "A false balance is an abomination
unto the Lord." A false balance is an
abomination unto the Lord. And so when
the Lord says, "Hey guys, this is my
balance.
Here is where the the majority of my
rebuke is going. going and my correction
is going and then there is where a
little of it is going. Why? Because they
don't even know the truth. But I have
called you to be witnesses to them.
That's why I put my attention on you.
That's why I'm trying to train you to be
like me. That's why I'm trying to train
you to reflect my character so that they
will see your light and come into the
truth and become one of you. But what
you're doing is you are exhibiting
darkness to them.
And beloved, I want you to understand
that it is that mind that that deception
that we can think we're in darkness
while walking while while professing to
serve Christ. I need you to see this in
John 18 verse 28. Then led they Jesus
from Caiaphas onto the hall of judgment.
And it was early and they themselves
went not into the judgment hall lest
they should be defiled but that they
might eat the Passover. Do you see this?
while claiming to not want to be defiled
by touching or being in the presence of
Gentiles, of Muslims,
of unbelievers,
of atheists,
of the left,
of the ungodly, of the Marxist, of the
socialist,
not realizing that that very spirit was
defiling them already, but yet they had
to keep the Passover. over. Or how about
this one? John 19:31. Therefore, the
Jews, because it was a preparation that
the body should not remain upon the
cross on the Sabbath day, for the
Sabbath was a high day, besought Pilate
that uh that their legs might be broken
and that they might be taken away. And
then they GO BACK TO TRY TO KEEP THE
SABBATH.
We're observing the ritual, not
realizing that your heart is defiled.
When Mary takes the ointment and and and
and anoints Jesus's feet, you know what
Judas said? Here's what he said. John
12:5. What? Listen. John 12:4. Then
saith one of his disciples, Judas's
scariot, Simon's son, which should
betray him. Why was not this ointment
sold for 300 p and given to the poor?
This he said, not that he cared for the
poor,
not that you actually cared.
It's a Sabbath. [snorts]
Religious liberty.
Religious liberty. That's an issue
worthy of Sabbath of of of of discussion
on Sabbath.
Ellen White talked about the the the
women's uh uh temperance movement and
inviting them to our camp meetings
because it will be good to to make
connections with them.
And yet we we we we
how dare
how
when that's not really the issue. the
real issue. Could it be possible that
the real issue is is if that picture was
with was with someone else
that it would not have been a problem?
Maybe someone of a different party. I
had people say, "Why did you take a
picture with someone of a different
party?" I couldn't because they didn't
come. They were invited. I would have
loved to
Would
you take a picture with a Ku Klux Clan
guy? Yep.
Yes, sir.
If I can make a connection with a Clue
Ku Klux Clan guy and win him to the
truth, you better believe it.
You better believe it,
beloved. We don't seem to understand. So
many of us don't seem to understand how
much our crying out against politics is
so hypocritical because we're actually
guided by politics
while claiming, "Oh, I'm not political,
but why don't you take a picture with
this person and only that person?"
Really? Really?
Are we Are we being serious right now?
God wants people on the left saved and
he wants people on the right saved. And
he has a pattern. God wants God wants
Christians who are not of our faith
saved. And he wants unbelievers who are
not of our faith saved. But he says to
the church, listen, I have called you to
preach a special message to Babylon.
Babylon is not the unbeliever, you guys.
Babylon is the fallen churches. Why?
Because the unbelievers are looking at
the big at the largest group of
professed followers of Jesus and seeing
nothing but hypocrisy.
And so we're trying to say, "Listen,
y'all bigger body of believers. What
you're doing is pushing them away. Here
is the actual truth. That's why God
wants us to focus over here."
But no, what we're doing is we're
adopting the hatred of that bigger group
of Christians and we're going, "Yeah,
those evil unbelievers. Literally not
even thinking how Satan is just
destroying the work that God has called
us to do." We're not thinking.
We're not thinking.
Ellen White says, "The greatest
deception of the human mind in Christ's
day was that a mere ascent to the truth
constitutes righteousness. In all human
experience, a theoretical knowledge of
the truth has been proved to be
insufficient for the saving of the soul.
It does not bring forth the fruits of
righteousness. A jealous regard for what
is termed theological truth is often or
often accompanies a hatred of genuine
truth as is made manifest in the life."
What does she mean? Here's what she
says. The darkest chapters of history
are burdened with the record of crimes
committed by bigoted religionists. The
Pharisees claimed to be the children of
Abraham and boasted of their possession
of the oracles of God. Yet these
advantages did not preserve them from
selfishness, maligny, greed for gain,
and the basis hypocrisy. They thought
themselves the greatest religionist of
the world, but their so-called orthodoxy
led them to crucify the Lord of glory.
The same dangers still exist today. Many
take it for granted that they are
Christians simply because they
subscribed to certain theological
tenants, but they have not brought the
truth into practical life. They have not
believed it and loved it and therefore
have not received the power and grace
that comes through sanctification of the
truth. Men may profess faith in the
truth, but if it does not make them
sincere, kind, patient, forbearing,
heavenly minded, it is a curse to its
possessor, and through their influence,
it is a curse to the world.
Beloved, I need you to understand
that I'm speaking with passion because
what is happening in our church, when
you make a man an offender because of a
word, when you make a man an offender
because of a picture and you start to
fill in the blanks and Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Really? I was checking it out and and
him and this guy go way back. they
actually really know each other and we
start going down the rabbit hole of the
conspiracies. I'm telling you beloved,
Satan is planting a spirit within the
members of our church. And if we do not
wake up from it, you are running the
risk of eternal loss.
The spell
that so many of us are under must be
broken.
This man ate with sinners and we now
have the goods on him.
Reviewing Herald June 2, 1896. Jesus was
accused of eating with publicans and
sinners at as though it were a crime to
associate with the fallen. WHAT ARE YOU
doing with him, Jesus? Explain.
By this accusation, they insinuated that
Christ liked to associate with the
sinful and vile. He likes this deep down
inside. This is who Jesus is and he
doesn't even realize their wickedness
and he was insensible to their
wickedness. That's what she says. They
really he really like he likes the
publicans. This is evidence that he's
unbalanced. He's rebuking us all the
time. He's rebuking the church all the
time. But he's not saying nothing to the
sinners. If he were a true prophet, they
said he would harmonize with them. Do
what we want you to do. Preach what we
want you to preach. Pastor, why aren't
you preaching what I want you to preach?
If he were a true prophet, if he were a
true believer, if he was actually
present truth, he would harmonize
with them and he would treat the
publicans and sinners and Muslims and
atheists and leftists and socialists and
Marxists with the indifference they
deserved. It angered these guardians. I
never seen so many angry people in my
life like I have in the last week.
Wow.
It angered these guardians of society
that he with whom they were continually
in controversy, yet whose purity of life
a condemned them should meet in such
apparent sympathy with social outcasts.
How dare you meet with a social outcast?
No Adventist should be seen
with a social outcast.
They classed him with sinners because he
associated with sinners. But Jesus did
not seem at all abashed by the charge.
He looked keenly at his accusers and
said, "I came not to call the
self-righteous but sinners to
repentance."
They passed by the very ones who needed
help, who would receive the light that
they rejected, who were near the kingdom
of heaven, nearer the kingdom of heaven
than those who looked upon them as
sinners, whose society would contaminate
their morals.
You guys, Ellen White is a prophet,
y'all. She is a prophet.
She says, "Yet we should not exclude
ourselves from the world, for our
Christian experience is to be the light
of the world." This exactly what I've
been trying to say, you guys. We should
not exclude ourselves from the world,
for our Christian experience is to be
the light of the world.
The society of unbelievers will do us no
harm if we mingle with them for the
purpose of connecting them with God and
are strong enough to spiritually
withstand their influence.
[snorts] It was taught by the Jews that
before God's love is extended to the
sinner, he must first repent. He must
first cease to be a Muslim. He must
first cease to be a leftist. He must
first cease to be a socialist. He must
first cease to be a Marxist.
In their view, repentance is a work by
men which earned the favor of heaven.
And it was this thought that led the
Pharisees to exclaim in astonishment and
anger, "This man receiveth sinners."
According to their ideas, he should
permit none to approach him. Why'd you
take a picture?
He should permit none to approach him
but those who had repented.
This is why Jesus says, "Beloved, many
will say in that day, Lord, Lord, have
we not in thy name cast out devils and
in thy name done many wonderful works?
Then I'll profess to them, depart from
me. I never knew you." I need you to
understand that people who claim the
name of Jesus and yet do not have the
character of Jesus will be rebuked by
Jesus when Jesus comes again.
All right.
So guys, now now I'm about to show you
something and please lock in.
We can now see why the books of Daniel
and Revelation focus not on the atheist,
not on the socialists, not on Marxism,
not on communism. It focused on a
counterfeit Christianity. And you'll
remember in Daniel 7:25 that this little
horn power, the Bible says, would speak
great words against the most high and
would think to wear out the saints and
think to change times and laws. And many
of us understand
that what this little horn power was
doing in changing times came up with two
new schools of thought. Futurism saying,
"No, it's not us. The enemy is in the
future." Predtoism, "No, it's not us.
The enemy is in the past." The thing
they were doing was they realized that
80% of the warnings of the books of
Daniel and Revelation were pointing to
them. And so they were trying to move
the finger from them and say, "No, guys,
look, the enemy is over there. The enemy
is in the past."
In the very same way,
in the very same way, could it be
possible
that the second power that comes up out
of the earth that is that claims to be a
Christian power,
could it be possible
that the devil is working through that
power to create enemies that aren't
really the enemies?
They are not the main enemies.
Beloved, I need you to understand that
that that what Christian nationalism,
what modern Christian, what apostate
Protestantism is doing right now is
they're saying, "Listen guys, the enemy
is atheism and socialism and Marxism and
Muslims. And those are the people we
need to be aware of." Why? because the
devil doesn't want the world to realize
that the real adversary is actually
working under the disguise of
Christianity. But God knew that. And so
he raised up a movement to say, "Guys,
stay focused.
I need you to call out Babylon because
nobody else is going to do it." the rest
of the Christian world, they're calling
out socialism and they're pretending
that these are the enemies when you know
that the actual enemy coming at the end
of time will be under the guise of
Christianity. So, so my Adventist
church, I need you to lock in and stay
focused. But you know what? Many of us
have been drinking the wine of Babylon
and are now demanding that God's 8010
scale become 5050 or better yet 9010.
That's what's happening. So now you
don't speak about about atheism enough
and you don't speak about homosexuality
enough and you don't speak you don't
condemn the homosexuals enough and you
don't condemn the atheists enough and
you're unbalanced because you're not
doing what the other churches out there
in the world are doing. You're why are
you so focused
on apostate Protestantism? Why are you
so focused on this second beast? Leave
the beast alone. Why don't you go deal
with with a that's balance. No, beloved,
that's apostasy.
That's moving away from the working of
the spirit, the spirit of God. It's it's
ratio in the Old Testament, in the in
the Gospels, in the New Testament, in
the great controversy, in the writings
of the spirit of prophecy. They It's
It's the same thing all across.
And now we want to change the ratio.
Now, we want to get mad
when our message is preached. How are
you going to get mad about somebody
preaching Revelation chapter 13? Because
you're like, "Well, you're not being
balanced." No. No.
When you drink the wine of Babylon, you
no longer know what balance is. You are
offbalance.
You are drunk with the wrath of Babylon.
And the wrath of Babylon is a wrath
directed at the Muslim. It's a wrath
directed at the atheist. And now you've
adopted that wrath. That's a Muslim.
What are you doing with them? That's an
atheist. Oh, that's the left. What are
you doing with them? CC. You would take
a picture with a left, but you wouldn't
take a picture with the right.
Stupidity. Foolish arguments. Not
realizing that both souls need to be
saved.
You're you're willing to extend context
to individuals who it may easily be
said, "Oh, they're racist." No, no, no,
no, no, no, no. It's the context,
context, context. But all you need is
one one thing
for a fellow believer in the Lord, for a
fellow believer in the faith, and be
like, "See what we've been telling you.
See, I told you. I told you. It was just
a matter of time. I I told you.
But let me tell you something, you guys.
Satan will never trip up the work of
God.
He may trip us up. He may trip me up. He
may lead us to make decisions that we're
not the best. He But he'll never trip up
the work of God.
We can say amen and hallelujah to that.
My thing is let us not help Satan in his
work.
Let us not help Satan in his work.
Because who but Satan would want to
destroy the character and the reputation
of fellow believers in the church?
You help me understand that
that is the work of the enemy. That is
the work of the devil.
We're getting ready to close. You guys,
I need y'all to understand this.
Uh there have been apparitions of Mary.
And in these apparitions of Mary, I'm
not going to go into in fact let me let
me just I'm going to pull one up here.
This is from the Fatima, one of the
Fatima visions. And I'm going to put it
up on the screen. You'll see it here. In
an interview in 1946, Fatima Seir Lucia
dos Santos said, "What our lady wants is
that the Pope and all the bishops of the
world consecrate Russia to her
immaculate heart on one special day. If
this is done, she will convert Russia
and there will be peace. If it is not
done, the errors of Russia will spread
through every country in the world."
Asked whether this meant that the entire
world could be overrun by communism,
Lucia said yes. Lucia was also asked
about whether the United States would
also fail into fall into communist
hands. And again, her reply was yes.
Listen to me y'all. There are
administers who are taking this this
prophecy from Mary seriously.
who really believe that communism
is an endtime player and could very well
take over America if we and you guys
it's it's absolutely mind-blowing
that for people who have been given the
spirit of prophecy
that she says almost nothing
about communism or mark if she's a
prophet
we would expect her to be able to warn
us along with Daniel and along with
Revelation of what comes at the end of
time. But here we are embibing in
Babylonian wine and now actually talking
about hey our greatest threat is
communism and Marxism and pastor why you
always talking about apostate
Protestantism.
In fact pastor you're an apostasy
because all you talk about is prophecy.
Isn't it? It It's stunning
that my whole ministry is based on
warning against the separate separation
of church and state.
Now, there's some articles out there
that are like, "Pastor blurs the line of
separation of church and state." No, no
context. Just hey, context doesn't
matter right now. What matters right now
is
we want to do the work of the enemy. And
that's the most important thing.
That that's that's a very dangerous
spirit, you guys. And it is a spirit
that is running rampant in our church.
It is a spirit that is being directed.
Listen, I know that you listen. Listen,
[clears throat] y'all.
Somebody needs to say something.
This spirit needs to stop. This spirit
of blood searching, of of of looking for
blood, because that's what it is.
We're looking for when ah we got the
dirt. Ah, look what we're making people
offenders for a word. And the spirit of
cannibalism needs to stop you guys.
Ellen White said this. As the storm
approaches, a large class who have
professed faith in the third angel's
message, but have not been sanctified
through obedience to the truth,
abandoned their position, and join the
ranks of the opposition. By uniting with
the world and partaking of its spirit,
they have come to view matters in nearly
the same light. And when the test is
brought, they are prepared to choose the
easy popular side. I need you to
understand what the easy popular side
is. The easy popular side will be
apostate Protestantism. That is the side
she is saying that many Adventists will
join with. Why? Because they so
connected themselves with their same
spirit with the spirit of wrath and the
spirit of anger and the spirit of hatred
towards the non-believer and the Muslim
and the homosexual and the atheist that
they lost the character of Christ and
now they have become so united. Listen,
right now you have Adventists protecting
and defending apostate Protestantism,
saying, "Stop preaching about that.
Focus on the things that really matter.
You're not being balanced."
Revelation 18:2, this is our closing
verse. This is our next closing verse.
Revelation 18:2, the Bible says about
this Babylon,
this Babylon, the great is fallen, has
fallen and has become the habitation of
devils and a hold of every foul spirit
and a cage of every unclean and hateful
bird. I need you to understand, beloved,
that Babylon is filled with a hateful
spirit. And many of us have adopted that
hateful spirit. It is seen. It is
publicly seen.
People are spotting it.
It is publicly being manifested
and towards God's church and towards
God's people.
We have been called with a message to
give a message that says, "Come out of
Babylon, my people." That's the message.
That is the message.
If Jesus said this, you are the light of
the world. A city set on a hill cannot
be hid. If Jesus says we're the light of
the world, and everyone who professes
Christ is supposed to be the light of
the world, then would it not make sense
that when the light of the world gets it
together, the Gentiles are going to
come. Would it not make sense? Isn't
that what God said? Isn't that why God
focuses so much on Babylon? come out of
her, my people, and get into the real
light so that the loud cry and the
Gentiles can be converted unto truth.
Isn't that what it's all about,
beloved? I'm making a special appeal.
And that appeal is this.
We need to put down the cup of wrath.
We need to put down the cup of of of of
wickedness. We need to put down
the spirit of perjury.
We need to focus
on cleansing our own characters.
We need to focus on preaching the
unadulterated
truth.
We need to stop with this false balance.
Well, you talked 50% about this. Why
don't you talk 50% about that? Jesus
didn't do that. The disciples didn't do
that. Ellen White didn't do that. Stop
with the false balances and begin to
follow the leading of the spirit.
The ratio is there for us.
Put down the cup.
Turn your weapons away from one another
and let us focus on the mission that God
has called us to do.
It is interesting
that a lot of the these things Oh,
Pastor Myers, he was standing with this
guy. Never never said go check out the
sermon.
Never said go listen to the sermon that
he preached.
A and and and and those who do who one
one individual actually said in his
sermon he did not talk about the sins of
ungodly people and therefore the sermon
is apostasy.
You guys we are we are drifting
very far away from the ideal that God
has for his church.
It is time to put down the cup.
It is time
to stop doing the work of the accuser of
the brethren. And it is time for us to
be about our father's business
to win souls
to speak truth and to be the light that
Jesus has called us to be.
That is my prayer.
And I'm going to put that I'm going to
ask you to put a one in the chat.
Pastor, that's me.
I've been drinking that cup.
I've had the spirit of anger. I've had
the spirit of of wrath. And I don't know
where it came from.
And along with that spirit of wrath
comes a spirit of accusation. It was in
the Pharisees and it's in many of God's
people now. And and we're making stuff
up in our minds and filling in blanks to
things that are not reality. and the
devil. This is the way the devil is
going to lead so many who claim to
believe in present truth to ultimately
join with the enemy at the end of time.
We ought to be praying for one another
and not praying on one another.
Heavenly Father,
Lord, forgive us as a people
for seeking
to catch a brother or a sister
for seeking to to to do harm, perjury.
Whether that is because it brings views
or whether it is because it makes people
feel like they are standing up for
present truth. Lord, rebuke that spirit.
Lord, what the enemy has taken for evil,
Lord, please turn that to good.
Lord, may may this instance be a lesson
to teach us how to plead the fifth
when it comes to our brothers and
sisters.
Teach us, Lord, to be willing to give
the benefit of the doubt to go talk to
the individual, Lord. But but but Lord,
please put that spirit of love within us
because that can only come from from the
spirit of love and so many of us are
lacking that love.
As a result of it, Lord, this claiming
the truth becomes a curse to those who
don't have the spirit of love and it is
a curse to the world through their
influence. Lord, please forgive your
people.
Thank you Lord for hearing this prayer
and Lord may we be about your business
is our prayer in Jesus name. Amen and
amen.
May God bless you as you continue to
draw closer to the Lord. May he bless
you and keep you.
We will put the link uh to the afterglow
uh in the chat and uh we want to
encourage uh our members and anyone who
would like to to come and join us as we
fellowship. We'll talk about the Sabbath
school. We'll talk about the divine
service. Again, may God bless you and
keep you. Amen.
Thank you for joining us today. If this
is your first time worshiping with us,
please check out our website at living
manana.urch. We are not just here for
Sabbath service. We have [music] weekly
programming too that covers mental
health, physical health, weekly prayer
service, financial health, and proving
the existence of God. It is our desire
that our programming will continue to
bless you. Please continue to pray for
us as we fulfill God's mission to go
into all the world with the gospel of
Jesus Christ.
>> [music]
[music]